Thank you very much
and welcome
to To Tell the Truth.
Our first guest,
he's made a career
out of being
the most outrageous impostor
that we've ever come across
on this show
and you're going to see
what I mean.
Number One
what is your name, please?
My name is
Frank William Abagnale.
Number Two?
My name is
Frank William Abagnale.
Number Three?
My name is
Frank William Abagnale.
"From 1964 to 1967
"I successfully impersonated
"an airline pilot
for Pan Am Airways
"and I flew over
two million miles for free.
"During that time, I was also
the chief resident pediatrician
"at a Georgia hospital
"and an assistant
attorney general
"for the state of Louisiana.
"By the time I was caught,
I was considered
"the youngest and most daring
con man in U.s. history.
"I had cashed almost $4 million
in fraudulent checks
"in 26 foreign countries
and all 50 states.
"And I did it all
before my 19th birthday.
My name is
Frank William Abagnale."
You don't know how
to tell the truth...
so, for the first time
he's going to have
to tell the truth
and we're going to start
our questioning with Kitty.
Thank you. Number One,
why, with all your talent...
and you're obviously
a very bright fellow...
why didn't you go in
for a legitimate profession?
It was really a question
of dollars and cents.
When I was a young man,
I needed the money
and I thought
this list of careers
was the easiest way to get it.
I see.
Number Two, I find this all
very fascinating.
Who was it
that finally caught you?
His name was Carl Hanratty.
Han-an-an-ratty.
Ratty.
Hanratty.
Han-ratty.
Carl Hanratty.
- Yes.
- I...
am... Carl Hanratty.
I represent the FBI from
the United states of America.
Yeah. I have orders
to see the American
prisoner, Abagnale.
You sit here.
You do not open the door.
You do not pass him...
anything through the hole.
Aw... Jesus.
You know, I've got
a little bit of a cold myself.
- Frank...
I'm here to read
the articles of extradition
according to the
European Court for Human Rights.
"Article One:
Extradition shall be granted
"in respect of offenses
punishable under the laws..."
elp me.
"...for the maximum period
of at least one year
of a severe penalty."
Help me.
Frank... stop it.
You don't think actually
you can fool me, do you?
16 pages to go.
stay with me.
Article Two:
"If the request for extradition
"includes several separate
offenses
each of which is punishable
under the laws..."
"of the requesting party..."
Frank?
Goddamn it!
- Get me a doctor in here!
- I need a doctor!
- Yes.
Doctor! Now!
Don't sweat it, Frank.
We're going to get you
right to a doctor.
Frank, if you can
hear me, don't worry.
I'm going to take you
home in the morning.
Home in the morning, Frank.
What are you doing?
Washing off the lice.
This man has to be on a plane
for America.
He has to see a doctor.
The doctor comes in tomorrow.
I have worked too long, too hard
for you to take this
away from me.
If he dies,
I'm holding you responsible.
Monsieur!
Ah, Frank.
Okay, Carl...
let's go home.
MAN:
The New Rochelle Rotary Club
has a history
that goes back to 1919.
In all those years
we've only seen a handful
of deserving gentlemen
inducted as lifetime members.
It's an honor that, uh
that has seen 57 names enshrined
on the wall of honor
and tonight, we make it 5:
so please stand as I present
my very good friend
a man who keeps
our pencils sharp...
and our pens in ink...
Frank William Abagnale.
I stand here humbled
by the presence
of Mayor Robert Wagner...
...and our club president,
Jack Barnes.
Most of all, I'm honored to see
my loving wife Paula...
...and my son, Frank Jr...
Frank... Aw, stand up.
Come on...
...sitting in the front row.
Two little mice fell
in a bucket of cream.
The first mouse quickly gave up
and drowned.
The second mouse...
wouldn't quit.
He struggled so hard
that eventually he churned
that cream into butter
and crawled out.
Gentlemen, as of this moment,
I am that second mouse.
You're a better dancer
than your father, Frankie.
You hear that, Daddy?
Like fun.
The girls don't know
what they're in for.
show him the dance
you were doing when we met.
Ah, who can remember?
The people
in that little French village
were so happy to see Americans
they decided
to put on a show for us.
so they crammed 200 soldiers...
Yeah, we know the story, Daddy.
...into that tiny social hall
and the first person
to walk onstage
is your mother,
and she starts to dance.
You know, it had been months
since we'd even seen a woman
and here's this blonde angel.
Blonde bombshell.
And the men are literally
holding their breath.
Holding their breath for you.
You hear that?
Mm-hmm.
And I turned to my buddies
and I said...
"I will not leave France
without her."
And I didn't.
You didn't.
I didn't.
Oh, shit! Oh, shit, the rug!
Aw, Mom...
I can't believe I did that.
No, no, it's nothing.
It's nothing.
Oh, Frankie, Frankie,
get a towel.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Paula...
Come on.
My sweet embraceable you...
Dance with me, Paula.
Ah...
Whenever I dance for you
I get in trouble.
Watch this.
Oh!
Frank! Wake up.
Come on, let's go!
Get up. Come on, come on.
Frank, wake up.
Dad...
You don't have to go
to school today.
It's okay.
Why? Is it snowing?
Do you have a black suit?
I overslept again, huh?
We have a very important
meeting in the city.
Eat that.
Come on, come on, eat.
Ma'am, open up.
Just open up, please!
- Ma'am?
- It's important.
What?
Oh, gosh!
We don't open
for half an hour!
Open the door, please.
Just open the door.
It's important.
I-I'm sorry, we don't open
for half an hour.
What's your name, ma'am?
Darcy.
Darcy. That's a pretty name.
I'm in a bit of a fix.
I need a suit for my kid.
This is my son Frank.
Oh, hi.
He needs a black suit.
Black suit...
There was a death in the family.
My father, :5 years old,
war hero.
Yeah?
There's a funeral
this afternoon, military funeral
planes flying overhead,
21-gun salute.
Geez.
Frank needs to borrow a suit
for a couple of hours.
I'm sorry, we don't loan suits,
and we're not open.
Darcy... Darcy, please.
- Come back.
Darcy... is this yours?
I just found it
in the parking lot.
Uh-huh.
It must've slipped
right off your neck.
Don't hit the curb.
Now get out,
walk around the back
and hold the door open for me.
All right.
What's next?
Okay, stop grinning.
When I get inside, you go back
to the front seat and wait.
Even if a cop comes
and writes you a ticket
you don't move the car,
understood?
Dad, wha-what's all this for?
You know why the Yankees
always win, Frank?
'Cause they have Mickey Mantle?
No, it's 'cause the other teams
can't stop staring
at those damn pinstripes.
Watch this.
The manager
of Chase Manhattan Bank
is about to open the door
for your father.
Mr. Abagnale, um
we don't usually
loan money to people
who have unresolved business
with the IRs.
That's a misunderstanding.
I hired the wrong guy
to do my books.
A mistake, I...
anybody could make it.
I just need you guys
to help me weather the storm.
sir, you're being investigated
by the government for tax fraud.
My store is a landmark
in New Rochelle.
I have customers
all over New York.
Well, you're not a customer
at Chase Manhattan.
We don't know you.
I'm sure your bank
in New Rochelle
they know you,
they could help you out.
My bank went out of business.
Banks like this one put
them out of business.
Now, I know I made a mistake,
I admit that
but these people want blood.
They want my store.
They've threatened
to put me in jail.
This is America, right?
I'm not a criminal.
I'm a Medal of Honor winner
a lifetime member
of the New Rochelle Rotary Club.
All I'm asking is for you
to help me beat these guys.
It's not a question
of winning and losing.
It's a question of risk.
You're the largest bank
in the world.
Where's the fu...
Whe... Where's the risk?
Dad, how could you just let him
take our car like that?
He didn't take anything.
We took him.
He overpaid by $500.
Come on, Frank.
Let's return the suit.
This place is good.
It's small but, you know
it's going to be
a lot less work.
A lot less work for you.
Hey, Dad.
Hi.
Where's your mother?
I don't know.
she said something
about going to look for a job.
What's she gonna be
a shoe salesman
at a centipede farm?
What are you doing?
You want some pancakes?
For dinner?
On my son's 16th birthday?
We're not gonna eat pancakes.
Come on, why are you looking
at me like that?
You thought I forgot?
- I didn't think you forgot.
- I opened a checking account
in your name.
I put $25 in the account
so you can buy
whatever you want.
Don't tell your mother.
I won't.
Thanks, Dad.
Yep.
Didn't that bank turn you down
for a loan, though?
Yes, they all turned me down.
Then why you opening
a banking account with them?
Well, because one day,
you'll want something
from these people...
a house, a car.
They have all the money.
There's 50 checks there, Frank
which means, from this day on...
you're in their little club.
I'm in their little club.
You got that, you got it all.
It's even got my name there,
huh?
To the moon.
- To the moon!
- To the moon.
see that? It's just a school.
No different than Westbourne.
Ma... you said you were
going to quit.
Frankie, you don't have
to wear the uniform here.
Why don't you take off
your jacket?
I'm used to it.
Excuse me.
Oh, yes?
Do you know
where room 17 French is?
Yeah, it's...
But you frickin' killed him.
You selling encyclopedias?
Yeah, he looks like
a substitute teacher.
Quiet down, people!
My name is Mr. Abagnale!
That's Abagnale, not Abagnahlee
not Abagnaylee, but Abagnale!
Now, somebody please tell me
where you left off
in your textbooks.
Excuse me, people,
if I need to ask again
I'm going to write up
the entire class.
Take your seats!
Chapter seven.
Will you please open your
textbooks to, uh, chapter eight
and we'll get started?
Excuse me,
what's your name?
Brad.
Brad, why don't you get up here
in front of the class here
and read conversation
number five?
:
"Les Francais sonts
"uh, generalement
- "dans leur pais que...
presque tout le monde
a cette impression..."
They sent for me.
They said they needed a sub
for Roberta.
I came all the way
from-from Dixon.
Well, uh,
I always sub for Roberta.
Excuse me,
why aren't you reading?
I'll never come back to-to
Bellarmine Jefferson again!
- You tell them not to call me!
What do they think,
it's easy for a woman my age
and all the money that it costs
to travel?
I tell you,
they don't give a damn.
Mr. And Mrs. Abagnale
this is not a question
of your son's attendance.
I regret to inform you that,
for the past week
Frank has been teaching
Mrs. Glasser's French class.
He what?
Your son has been pretending
to be a substitute teacher
lecturing the students,
uh, giving out homework.
Mrs. Glasser has been ill
and there was
some confusion
with the real sub.
Your son held a teacher-parent
conference yesterday
and was planning
a class field trip
to a French bread factory
in Trenton.
Do you see the problem we have?
- Mrs. Davenport?
- Yeah.
Uh, I have a note to miss fifth
and sixth period today.
Doctor's appointment.
- One moment.
I'll be right with you.
Hey...
Yes?
You should fold it.
What?
That note. It's a fake, right?
You should fold it.
It's... It's a note from my mom.
I have a doctor's appointment.
Yeah, but there's no crease
in the paper.
When your mom hands you a note
to miss school
the first thing you do is,
you fold it
and you put it in your pocket.
I mean, if it's real,
where's the crease?
Frankie.
Ma, I'm home.
Oh, you remember
that girl Joanna
I was telling you about?
I asked her out today.
Think we're going to go
to the Junior Prom.
Ma, is this
my driver's license?
That's all there is,
two bedrooms.
Oh, Frankie.
You remember Dad's friend?
Jack Barnes?
From the club.
Hello.
He came by looking
for your father.
I was giving him
a tour of the apartment.
It's very, uh, uh,
spacious, Paula.
Dad's at the store.
so, Frank...
you're getting to look
more like your old man
every day.
Thanks for the sandwich, Paula.
I'll see you later, eh?
Wait.
Is this yours?
Oh.
Well, thanks, Frank.
Uh, that's the President's pin.
I'd be in deep trouble
if I lost that.
I'll see you all later, eh?
Are you hungry, Frankie?
I'll make you a sandwich.
Jack wanted to talk business
with your father.
He thinks we should get a lawyer
and sue the government.
That is not legal,
what they're doing to us.
Why aren't you saying anything?
You're not going to tell him...
are you?
No.
That's right.
There's nothing to tell.
I'm going out for a few hours
to visit some old friends
from the tennis club and...
when I get home,
we'll all have dinner together.
Right?
But you won't say anything
because it's...
it's just silly, isn't it?
How could we sue anybody?
Oh... do you need
some money, Frankie?
A few dollars to buy
some record albums?
Here, take five dollars.
Or-Or ten.
You promised you were going
to quit.
Ma, I'm home!
Hey, hey!
You... You stay away from me,
hear me?
You stay away from me...
I don't know who you are
but if you ever
come back here again...
Frankie! Frank, Frank,
calm down, will you?
I'm Dick Kesner.
Now, I want you
to leave your things here
and follow me
into the next room, okay?
They're all waiting for you.
You don't have to be scared.
I'm right here, Frank.
I'll always be here.
But there are laws.
Everything in this country has
to be legal.
so what we need to do is
make some decisions.
That's what Mr. Kesner
is here for.
Many times these decisions
are left up to the courts
but that can be
very expensive, Frank
people fighting
over their children.
Nobody is fighting.
Look at me, Frank.
Dad, what's going on?
Do you remember your grandma,
Eve?
she arrived this morning.
Hello.
Do you understand what
we're saying to you, Frank?
Your father and I
are getting a divorce.
Nothing's gonna change.
We're still gonna see
each other.
stop it, please, Frank.
Don't interrupt.
Frank, you don't
have to read all of this.
Most of it's for your parents...
boring adult business...
but this paragraph right here,
this is important
because it states
who you're gonna live with...
after the divorce...
whose custody you will be in.
And there's a blank space
right here.
And I want you to go
into the kitchen
sit at the table
and put a name down.
You can take
as long as you want
but when you come back
into this room...
I want to see a name
on that line.
Frank, just write down a name
and this will all be over.
It's gonna be okay.
FRANK:
Dad, what name?
Your mother or your father.
Just put the name there.
It's as simple as that.
And don't look so scared.
It's not a test.
There's no wrong answer.
Hi.
One ticket to Grand Central,
please.
That'll be $3.50, sir.
Is it okay
if I write you a check?
Carl, when do I get
to call my father?
You can call him
when we get to New York.
We leave for the airport
in seven hours.
Until then, just sit there.
Be quiet.
You know, Carl,
on the other side of the hotel
they got suites
that face the park.
It's the best room
the FBI can afford.
It's okay, I've stayed in worse.
Mr. Mudrick...
Mr. Mudrick, please.
You have to listen.
I don't want to hear your story.
This is two checks that bounced.
You know how much trouble
I'm in?
No, but listen, I'm telling you,
the bank, they made the mistake.
I'll write you another check
right now!
What, do I look like
I was born yesterday?
Look, it's midnight,
Mr. Mudrick.
Where am I gonna go?
You're a goddamn kid.
Go home.
I mean, I hope you understand.
My boss sent me to Brooklyn,
then Queens.
Now he wants me in Long Island
to take a few clients out
for a night on the town.
I'm sorry, but we're not allowed
to cash checks from other banks.
How would we know
if they were any good?
What did you say your name was?
Ashley.
Ashley... you know what I found
on the sidewalk out there?
Must've slipped
right off your neck.
Is there something
I can help you with, son?
Well, you see, it's my
grandmother's birthday next week
and I want to get her
something extra-special.
Please, I mean
it's my midterm next week
and my books were stolen.
Please, it's just five dollars.
No one would have to know.
I'm sorry,
but we are not allowed
to take checks
from people we don't know.
Pleasure to have you back,
Captain Carlson.
What do you think, Angelo?
The tomatoes are ripe
this afternoon.
Well, what have we here?
- Can I have your autograph?
- You betcha.
- Can I have your autograph, too?
- You gonna be a pilot?
- Mm-hmm!
- All right, then.
There you go.
Work hard in school.
Dear Dad:
I have decided to become
an airline pilot.
I have applied
to all the big airlines
and I have several
promising interviews lined up.
How's Mom?
Have you called her lately?
Love, your son, Frank.
Hello.
I'm Frank Black
from Murrow High school
and I have an appointment
with Mr. Morgan.
You're the young man
who's writing the article
for the school paper.
Yes, ma'am, that's me.
I want to know
everything there is to know
about being a pilot.
What airports
does Pan Am fly to?
What does a pilot make
in a year?
And who tells them
where they're gonna fly to?
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Slow down.
Just take 'em one at a time.
All right. What does it mean
when one pilot says
to another pilot:
"What kind of equipment
are you on?"
They just want to know what kind
of aircraft you're flying:
Is it a DC-:707,
Constellation?
And what about those I.D. badges
that I've seen pilots wear?
Well, every pilot has to have
two things with him
at all times: One is
his airline personnel badge...
Looks just like this one here,
from Pan Am...
the other one is
their FAA license...
and that looks just like this.
Oh. Sir, do you think I can
make a copy of this
to put into my article?
Oh, Frank,
you can have that one.
It's three years expired.
Aw, thanks!
And what about your I.D. badge?
You have an extra one
I could borrow?
Oh, no, I can't help you there.
Those are special-ordered
from Polaroid.
The only way
to get one of those
is to become a real live pilot
for Pan American Airways.
Pan Am, may I help you?
Yeah, hello.
I'm calling about a uniform.
Hold for Purchasing.
Thank you.
Purchasing.
Hi. I'm a copilot
based out of san Francisco.
I flew a flight
into New York last night
but the problem is
I'm headed out to, uh, Paris
in three hours.
How can we help you?
I sent my uniform
to be cleaned through the hotel
and I... I guess
they must have lost it.
They lost a uniform.
Happens all the time.
Go down to the Well-Built
Uniform Company
at Ninth and Broadway.
They're our uniform supplier.
I'll tell Mr. Rosen
you're coming.
You look too young
to be a pilot.
I'm a copilot.
Why so nervous?
How would you feel if you, uh
Lost your uniform
first week on the job?
Relax.
Pan Am's got lots of uniforms.
It's gonna be $164.
Great. I'II, uh,
I'll write you a check.
sorry, no checks, no cash.
You'll have to fill in
your employee I.D. number
and then I'll bill Pan Am.
They'll take it out
of your next paycheck.
Even better.
Dear Dad:
You always told me that an
honest man has nothing to fear.
So I'm trying my best
not to be afraid.
I'm sorry I ran away,
but you don't have to worry.
I'm gonna get it all back
now, Daddy.
I promise.
I'm going to get it all back.
Are you a real live pilot?
I sure am, little lady.
What's your name?
Celine.
Celine, it's a pleasure
to meet you.
It's a pleasure
to meet you, too.
That's fifty, seventy
eighty, ninety,
one hundred dollars.
You have yourself a great time
in Paris.
I always do.
Excuse me.
I'm John Modiger.
I manage this branch.
I want to thank you
for coming in
and using our institution.
Well, it's a pleasure
to meet you, John.
I'll be back again.
Good.
Have you stayed with us before?
Uh, no, I've been primarily
based on the West Coast.
Is it all right if I write you
a check for the room?
No problem, sir.
Great.
Uh...
I was also wondering
if I could write you
a personal check?
For airline personnel, we cash
personal checks up to $100.
Payroll checks
we cash up to $300.
Did you say $300
for a payroll check?
Dear Dad:
I've decided to become a pilot
for Pan American Airways...
the most trusted name
in the skies.
They've accepted me
into their training program
and told me that if I work hard
I should earn my wings
real soon.
Please get in touch with Joanna
Carlton from the tenth grade.
Tell her I'm sorry that I could
not take her to the Junior Prom.
Love, your son, Frank.
Hello, how are you?
Fine, thank you.
I have a payroll check here
I'd like to cash.
Certainly.
Thank you.
Uh, excuse me.
I'm sure you hear this
all the time
but you have the most
beautiful eyes I have ever seen.
Yeah, I do get that
all the time.
How would you like it?
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
We won't have any cash until
the banks open in an hour
but, uh, I'm sure
they can cash your check
at the airport.
The airport?
Who cashes checks
at the airport?
Well, the airlines, sir.
They've always taken care
of their own.
Hello.
Hi. Are you deadheading?
What?
Are you my deadhead to Miami?
Mi...?
Yes, yes.
Yeah, I'm the deadhead.
Here you go.
You're a little late,
but the jump seat is open.
You know
it's been awhile
since I've done this.
Which one's the jump seat again?
Have a nice flight.
Are you my deadhead?
Frank, Captain Oliver.
- John Larkin, the copilot.
- Hello.
Fred Tulley, flight engineer.
Frank Taylor, Pan Am.
Thanks for giving me a lift,
boys.
Go ahead and take a seat, Frank.
We're about to push.
What kind of equipment you on,
DC-:?
Uh, 707.
You turning around
on the redeye?
Uh, I'm jumping puddles
for the next few months
trying to earn my keep
running leapfrogs
for the weak and weary.
No shame in that.
We all did it.
Have a seat.
Thank you.
Would you like a drink
after takeoff?
M-Milk?
0 knots.
Check.
V-one. Rotate.
V-two. Positive rate.
Gear up.
Dear Dad:
Today was graduation.
I am now a copilot
earning $1,400 a month
plus benefits
and the best part is
they tell me
my family can fly for free.
So tell Mom to pack her bags
and buy a new swimsuit
because I'm taking us all
to Hawaii for Christmas.
I love you, Dad.
Aloha, Frank.
Hello, deadhead.
Hello.
Enjoying your free ride?
Marci...
did you drop this?
Must've slipped
right off your neck.
No...
No!
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
Yes!
Why are you stopping?
I want to tell you something,
Marci.
This is by far...
the best date I have ever
been on.
I'd like to open a Money Market,
please.
Okay.
Welcome to Miami Mutual Bank.
How may I help you?
My name is Frank Taylor.
I'm a copilot for Pan Am.
I'd like to cash
this check here, and then
I'd like to take you out
for a steak dinner.
And then we feed the checks
into the MICR machine
which uses special ink
to encode the account numbers
on the bottom of the checks.
And where are these numbers?
They're, um... right here.
Right there?
see?
They're called routing numbers.
so where do the checks
get routed to?
You know, I don't exactly know.
Nobody ever
asked me that before.
Our next item up for bid
is also from the Jersey
Central Bank foreclosure.
This is a MICR encoder
a machine used
to encode bank checks.
Do I have an opening bid?
Our unknown subject
is a paperhanger
who started working
on the East Coast.
In the last few weeks,
this unsub has developed
a new form of check fraud
which I'm calling "the float."
What he's doing is
he's opening checking accounts
at various banks
then changing the MICR ink
routing numbers
at the bottom of those checks.
Next slide, please.
Uh, the remote thing is broken.
You'll have to do it by hand.
You've gotta... try the...
Agent Mullen, it should be...
it should be the square button
just there by the side.
This carousel doesn't work.
It's a bad carousel
you got there.
Thank you, Agent Mullen.
Got to move it manually.
This is a map of the 12 banks
of the U.s. Federal Reserve.
slide.
MICR scanners at every bank
read these numbers
at the bottom of a check...
slide...
and then, ship that check off
to its corresponding branch.
Carl, for those of us who are
unfamiliar with bank fraud
you mind telling us
what the hell
you're talking about?
The East Coast branches are
numbered zero-one to zero-six.
The central branch
is zero-seven, zero-eight
so on, so forth.
You mean those numbers
on the bottom of a check
actually mean something?
All of this was in the report
I filed two days ago.
If you change...
a zero-two to a one-two
that means that check,
which was cashed in New York
does not go
to the New York Federal Branch
but it is rerouted
all the way to the san Francisco
Federal Branch.
The bank doesn't even know the
check has bounced for two weeks
which means our unsub can stay
in one place
paper the same city
over and over again
while his checks circle
the country.
You know,
you want to talk to my wife.
she's the one balances
the checkbook at our house.
Next slide.
Daddy!
My son, the birdman.
some uniform, Frank.
What do you think?
Nice.
sit down.
so, Dad... Daddy, have you
gotten the postcards?
Of course.
This fork is ice cold.
No, no, Dad, th-that's
a chilled salad fork.
It's a fancy restaurant,
you know.
Well, here...
I-I got you something.
What's that?
Open it.
You know what those are, right?
Those are the keys
to a 1965 Cadillac
DeVille convertible.
Brand-new, Dad.
Red with white interior
split seats,
air conditioning, the works.
Are you giving me a Cadillac?
Yeah. I'm giving you a Cadillac.
Dad, sh-she's parked downstairs.
When we're done eating lunch
why don't you, you know,
drive on over to Mom's house
pick her up,
take a little joyride?
Do you know what would happen
if the IRs found out
I was driving around
in a new coupe?
I took the train here, Frank.
I'm taking the train home.
All right.
I have plenty of money.
You know, if you
ever, ever need anything...
You worried?
About me?
No, I'm not... I'm not worried.
You think I can't buy
my own car?
Two mice fell
in a bucket of cream, Frank.
Which one am I?
You're that second mouse.
I went by the store today.
I had to close the store
for awhile.
It's all about timing, Frank.
The goddamn government
knows that.
They hit you when you're down.
I wasn't going to let them
take it from me, so I just...
shut the doors myself,
called their bluff.
sooner or later,
they'll forget about me.
I understand, I...
Have you told Ma?
she's so stubborn, your mother.
Don't worry.
I'm not going to let her go
without a fight.
I been fighting for us...
Dad?
...since the day we... we met.
Daddy, out of all those men
you were the one that
took her home, remember that.
200 men, sitting in
that tiny social hall
watching her dance.
What was the name of that town?
Montrichard, Dad.
Yeah.
I didn't speak a word of French
and six weeks later,
she was my wi...
she's your wife.
My son bought me
a Cadillac today.
I think that calls for a toast.
To the best damn pilot
in the sky.
It's not what you think.
I'm just a copilot.
You see these people staring
at you?
These are
the most powerful people
in New York City
and they keep peeking
over their shoulders
wondering where
you're going tonight.
Where you going, Frank?
Dad, nobody's staring at me.
some place exotic?
Just tell me where you're going.
Los An... Hollywood.
Hollywood.
The rest of us...
really are suckers.
so, I got on this red dress
and these high heels, right?
And I got a bra,
like, out here, okay?
And I'm chasing
these two Puerto Rican guys
through the park.
They got a suitcase filled
with bank robbery loot.
Okay, I'm screaming out,
"FBI, freeze!"
And I'm reaching for my gun,
but I can't find it in the bra.
It's so damn big
I thought I was going
to shoot my tits off.
You know, that's a funny story.
People always laugh
at that story.
Let me ask you a question,
Mr. Amdursky.
If you were having
so much fun undercover
why did you transfer
to bank fraud?
I didn't transfer.
I was censured
and reassigned.
It's like being punished.
I was punished.
I screwed up in the field.
What about you, Mr. Fox?
Were you... punished
for screwing up in the field?
Oh, no, no, no, I've never
worked in the field before.
I audited
background investigations
of Department of Justice
clerical applicants.
Well, that's just great.
I ask for a team
and they drag the bottom
of the Pacific.
You mind if I ask you
a question, Agent Hanratty?
How come you're so serious
all the time?
Does it bother you,
Mr. Amdursky?
Yeah. Yeah, it does bother me.
Does it bother you, Mr. Fox?
A little, I guess.
Well, would you like
to hear me tell a joke?
Yeah. Yeah, we'd love
to hear a joke from you.
Knock, knock.
Who's there?
Go fuck yourselves.
Tall and tan
and young and lovely
The girl from Ipanema...
He cashed three checks.
They all cleared.
I was going to deposit
this one today.
I don't want any trouble.
No trouble.
No trouble at all.
We'll just take this check
and be on our way.
Thank you.
Good.
Because I don't want
my customers harassed.
...Each one she passes
goes ahh...
What are you saying,
he's still here?
201.
...Oh, but he watches
so sadly...
Thank you.
Corner here.
Oh, thanks, son.
...How can he tell her
he loves her...
some steps.
steps.
Hey, Mr. Murphy, how are you?
Is that Frank?
Yeah, it's Frank.
Hey, Frank, how are you?
How's the knee?
Come on,
I'll race you right now.
Take care.
Okay, Frank.
"Eyeball the back"?
Come on, Carl,
this guy's a pen and ink man.
A goddamn paperhanger.
He doesn't even carry a gun.
Why can't we go with you, Carl?
You just keep your eyes open,
do your job
and I'll buy you both
a Good Humor bar.
It's all right, ma'am. FBI.
201... 201, 201.
201...
201... 201... 201... 201...
FBI!
Come out of the bathroom!
step out of the bathroom!
Hands on your head.
Oh, that's the new
IBM selectric.
Put your hands on your head.
You can change the print type
in five seconds.
- Shut up!
- Just pop out the ball.
Put your hands on your head!
Put your hands...!
You know, he's got over 200
checks here, a gallon
- Of India ink, drafting.
- Hands on your head!
Even has
little payroll envelopes
addressed to himself
from Pan Am.
Put it down! Drop it!
Relax.
You're late, all right?
My name's Allen, Barry Allen
United states secret service.
Your boy just tried
to jump out the window.
My partner has him
in custody downstairs.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You think the FBI
are the only ones on this guy?
I mean, come on.
Come on, he's dabbling
in government checks here.
We've been following
a paper trail on this guy
for months now.
Hey, you mind taking that gun
out of my face?
Please. Really.
I mean, it makes me nervous.
Let me see some credentials.
Yeah, sure.
Take my whole wallet.
You want my gun, too?
Come over here. Take my gun.
Hey, hey, look,
just do me a favor.
Take a look outside. Look.
Look out the window.
My partner's walking him
to the car as we speak... Look.
Old guy almost pissed
in his pants
when I came through the door.
He jumped
right through the window
onto the hood of my car.
Hey, Murph?
- Yeah?
- Call the LAPD again.
I don't want people walking
through my crime scene.
I didn't expect
the secret service on this.
Don't worry about it.
Well, what's your name?
Hanratty, Carl Hanratty.
Mind if I see
some identification?
sure.
You never can be too careful
these days.
Well, tough luck, Carl.
Five minutes earlier
you would've landed yourself
a pretty good collar.
It's all right.
Ten seconds later,
and you'd have been shot.
Mind if I come downstairs
with you?
I-I got to take a look
at this guy.
sure thing.
Just, uh, do me a favor
and sit tight for a second
while I get
this evidence downstairs.
You know, I don't want
some maid walking through here
and making the bed.
LAPD should be here any sec.
Wait.
Your wallet.
You hang onto it for a minute.
I trust you.
Oh...
Yeah...
secret service.
Hey!
Oh, goddamn it!
It was stupid.
I made a stupid mistake.
Forget about it.
There are hundreds
of unknown subjects out there.
I-I can get this guy, sean.
The worst thing a paperhanger
can do is show his face.
I read the report.
six feet tall, brown hair,
27 to 30 years of age
160 pounds.
This could be almost anybody.
I heard his voice, sean,
I saw his face.
There's nothing for him
to hide behind anymore.
Just be careful.
You got 12 years in.
Nobody bothers you
down on the first floor.
You practically wrote the book
on bank fraud.
That's the kind of thing
that can make you
section chief someday.
Just don't put yourself
in this type of position.
What type of position?
Position of being humiliated.
sean, would you like
to hear me tell a joke?
Yeah, sure.
Knock, knock!
so, my-my next question is,
when a pilot retires
uh, Pan Am sends them
a check every single month?
Uh, yeah, pension program
sends a check and benefits.
How much is that check for?
Uh, kid, I'm really not
in the mood for this right now.
This skywayman's
driving me crazy.
Who's the skywayman?
Ah, some nut that's flying
around the country
posing as a Pan Am pilot.
There's a column about him
in the paper today.
I keep telling them
this is not my problem.
This guy
doesn't even fly Pan Am.
Flies everybody else.
Flies United, TWA,
Continental, Eastern...
The skywayman.
Newspaper loves this clown.
They call him
"the James Bond of the sky."
Did you say...?
Bond, James Bond.
Tell me, Joan,
why does he do it?
He likes to win.
Come on, come on.
We'll be landing
in 20 minutes.
Do you want to play it easy
or the hard way?
And this isn't a tranquilizer.
Well, Pussy, you do know a lot
more about planes than guns.
Hello, Pussy.
Now, you're sure
this is the suit, right?
Positive.
It's the exact suit he wore
in the movie.
Okay. I'll take three.
Certainly, Mr. Fleming.
Now what you need is
one of those
little foreign sports cars
that he drives.
The look of love
Is in your eyes...
Hello.
Hi.
...The look your heart...
Haven't I seen you before?
...Can't disguise...
Maybe.
A couple years ago, I was
on the cover of Seventeen.
Yeah.
You're that model, right?
Cheryl.
Yes.
The guys used to put
your picture on their lockers.
Isn't that your silver car
I saw parked out front?
Yeah. One of them.
Well, it takes
my breath away...
so, think I could get
an autograph?
...I can hardly wait
to hold you
Feel my arms around you...
Do you have a pen in your room?
...How long I have waited...
You've got the look of love
It's on your face
A look that time
can't erase...
shh.
...Be mine tonight...
Man like you can buy
anything he wants.
...Let this be
just the start
Of so many nights
like this...
He buys a deck of cards
at the hotel gift shop.
...And then seal it
with a kiss...
Well, you want
to see a card trick?
...I can hardly wait
to hold you...
How much did these cards cost?
...Feel my arms
around you...
Oh, 55 cents, I think.
...Waited just
to love you...
And if they sold me downstairs
at the hotel gift shop...
how much would you pay?
I'm sor...
I'm sorry, how mu...
how much would I pay for what?
The entire night.
How much would you pay me
for the entire night?
Cheryl, I...
I really don't know.
...I can hardly wait
to hold you...
Don't be scared.
...How long I have waited...
Make me an offer.
...Now that I have found you
Don't ever go...
$300?
Go fish.
Uh, $500?
$600.
Go fish.
$1,000.
Okay.
I'll be right back.
Wait a second.
Where are you going?
I'm going downstairs
to cash a check.
You think this hotel is going
to cash a $1,000 check
at 3:00am?
It's a New York savings and Loan
check.
It's like gold.
They'll cash it.
Don't you think they might get
a little suspicious?
Let me see that.
It's a cashier's check.
Endorse it over to me.
No. I couldn't do that.
see, this check is for $1,400.
We agreed upon $1,000.
Why don't I give you back $400
and you give me that check?
Even better.
The look of love
Is in your eyes...
Does this belong to anybody?
Mele Kalikimaka
is the thing to say...
On a bright
Hawaiian Christmas Day...
This is Hanratty.
Merry Christmas.
Hello, Carl.
Hello.
...That we send to you,
from the land...
Barry Allen, secret service.
I've been trying
to track you down now
for the last couple of hours.
What do you want?
I wanted to apologize
for what happened
out in Los Angeles.
Uh-uh, uh-uh.
No, no,
you don't apologize to me.
Do you always work
on Christmas Eve, Carl?
I volunteered
so men with families
could go home early.
Looked like you were wearing
a wedding ring
out in Los Angeles.
I thought maybe
you had a family.
No. No family.
You want to talk to me...
let's talk face-to-face.
All right.
I'm at my suite at the
stuyvesant Arms, room 3113.
In the morning, I leave
for Las Vegas for the weekend.
You think you're going
to get me again?
You're not going to Vegas.
You're not
in the stuyvesant Arms.
You'd love for me
to send out 20 agents
Christmas Eve
we barge into your hotel,
knock down the door
so you can make fools
out of us all.
I'm really sorry
if I made a fool out of you.
I really am.
Uh-uh, no.
No, listen, I really am.
No, no, you-you do not
feel sorry for me.
The truth is,
I knew it was you.
Now maybe I didn't get the cuffs
on you, but I knew.
Ah, people only know
what you tell them, Carl.
Well, then tell me this,
Barry Allen, secret service.
How did you know
I wouldn't look in your wallet?
The same reason
the Yankees always win.
Nobody can keep their eyes
off the pinstripes.
The Yankees win
because they have Mickey Mantle.
No one ever bets on the uniform.
You sure about that, Carl?
I'll tell you what I am sure of.
You're going to get caught.
One way or another,
it's a mathematical fact.
It's-It's like Vegas.
The House always wins.
Well, Carl, I'm sorry,
but I have to go.
Ah. You didn't call
just to apologize, did you?
What do you mean?
You... you...
you have no one else to call.
Oh, ho, ho.
...Morn and night...
You got that burger up?
Yep.
- Hi.
- Hi!
How are you?
...Doo-lang, doo-lang,
doo-lang...
The one
with the wavy hair...
More coffee, sir?
Are you a collector?
Of what?
"Captives of the Cosmic Ray,"
"The Big Freeze"
"Land of the Golden Giants."
I've got them all.
What are you talking about?
Barry Allen.
The Flash.
Wait, kid, kid, kid.
You mean like the comic book?
Yeah, the comic book.
When he's not The Flash.
That's his name, Barry Allen.
Thank you.
Now get this:
He reads comic books.
Comic books!
Barry Allen is The Flash!
Carl, slow down. Slow down.
I don't know what the hell
you're talking about.
He's a kid.
Our unsub is a kid.
That's why we couldn't match
his prints.
That's why he doesn't have
a record.
Now, I want you to contact NYPD
for every all-points juvenile
runaways in New York City.
And don't forget the airports.
He's been kiting checks
all over the country.
But why New York?
The Yankees!
He said something
about the Yankees!
so where are we on the list?
Number 53, "Abagnahlee."
Good morning, ma'am.
We're the FBI agents
who called.
Yes, I've been waiting.
I hope you're all hungry.
I put out the sara Lee.
My husband Jack is a lawyer.
What about your first husband,
Mrs. "Abagnahlee"?
Abagnale, but I prefer
to be called Barnes.
"Frank William Abagnale."
It says here
he was in the service.
Did... Did you two meet
during the war?
Yeah, I lived
in a very small village
in France... Montrichard...
the kind of place
where they never heard
of sara Lee.
Help yourselves.
"Nobody doesn't like sara Lee."
You filled out
a missing person's report
for a runaway juvenile by
the name of Frank Abagnale Jr.
Is Frankie okay?
You're aware of the fact
that he wrote some checks
on a closed account
at Chase Manhattan Bank?
Oh, yes.
The police think
he's some type of criminal.
What he did was a felony,
Mrs. Barnes.
It was $1,000.
Half the kids his age are
on dope
throwing rocks at police
and they scared me to death
because my son made
a little mistake.
Huh. A 17-year-old...
boy has to eat
has to have a place to sleep.
We understand, ma'am.
Would you happen to have
a picture of your son?
Oh, yes.
I have his old yearbook.
Okay.
Okay, okay, we, uh...
we need to send out
an all-office teletype.
Our unsub's name is
Frank Abagnale Jr., age 17.
Is Frankie okay?
Is he in trouble?
Ma'am, I'm sorry
to have to tell you:
Your son is forging checks.
Forging checks? Wait!
I'm sure we can take care
of that.
I am working part-time
at the church now.
Just tell me how much he owes
and I'll pay you back.
so far, it's about $1.3 million.
Girl, you really
got me goin'
You got me so
I don't know what I'm doin'
Yeah, you really
got me goin'
You got me
so I can't sleep at night...
Hi, Melanie, how are you?
When you're in the house,
please, just use an ashtray.
Frank, this fondue is so good!
Great. Here, take this for me.
Ooh, good! I love Moet!
Oh, yeah...
Hey. How are you?
You really got me goin'
You got me goin',
got me goin' and goin'...
James, James, please!
Just stay away from the
hi-fi system, all right?
It's reel-to-reel.
You can't wind it like that.
Don't ever set me free...
Christ! Terry!
This is Italian knit!
Watch where you're going!
It's just a shirt, man!
Frank! Come quick!
Lance just fell
into the conversation pit!
Excuse me, you know
where Lance Applebaum is?
Thank you.
These bottles need to be labeled
when you pick them up.
Do you understand
how dangerous this is?
Do you?
Don't stand there crying,
just nod your head
and tell me
you won't do it again.
Now dry up and get back to work.
Dr. Blair, Dr. Blair
Dr. Sherwood Blair.
Hey, hey... you okay?
He told me to pick up the blood,
so I did, but he never told me
to label it.
Hey, it's okay.
stop crying.
What's your name?
- Brenda.
Brenda, I wouldn't worry
about it.
You know, these doctors
you know,
they don't know everything.
It's my first week
and I think they're
going to fire me.
No, no, nobody's
going to fire you, Brenda.
I bet you're good at your job.
No, I'm not.
Yeah, I bet if I asked you
to check on the status
of my friend Lance Applebaum
that you could do that for me
in a second.
Nurse Fitzsimmons to Recovery.
Um...
Mr. Applebaum fractured
his ankle.
Dr. Ashland is treating him
in exam room seven.
You see that? No problem.
This is the emergency chart.
see that blue star there?
That means that the patient
has been diagnosed.
And then,
after he's been treated
we put a red circle here, see?
How do you like those braces?
I got mine off last year.
Boy, I hated them.
They were bottoms.
You know, I still got to wear
my mouth guard.
You have really nice teeth.
Well, thank you.
And you have a pretty smile.
Custodial to cafeteria.
No, I mean it.
I really think
those braces look good on you.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Brenda.
Yeah.
Do you know if they're hiring
here at the hospital?
I'm not sure.
What do you want to do?
I'm a doctor.
Dear Dad:
I've decided to get
off the road for awhile.
I've taken a night job
at a hospital
and met
some really nice people.
Feels good to have my feet
on the ground
to wake up in the same bed
every night.
Who knows, maybe I'll even find
someone to settle down with.
Harvard Medical school...
top of your class.
southern California
Children's Hospital.
Well, that's a pretty impressive
resume, Dr. Conners
but unfortunately, uh...
the only thing I need
is a...
an emergency room supervisor
for my midnight to: :00am shift
someone to baby-sit
six interns and 20 nurses
but, uh...
Hell, I doubt that, uh,
you would be interested in that.
Well, in the past
they've always let me choose
my own nurses.
Dr. Connelly?
Dr. Harris?
Present.
Dr. Ashland?
Dr. Conners...
You gonna take roll every night?
Uh, yes, I will, Dr. Ashland
and if you're going to be late,
I suggest you bring a note.
Miss Basmann.
Miss Mace.
Miss strong.
Here.
Nurse Brown.
- Nurse sanford?
- Here.
30 milligrams of codeine
every four hours.
Run the plasma
at 60 drops a minute
until we calculate
the fluid requirements.
What do you estimate
the degree and extent
of the burns, Kildare?
second and third-degree burns
over about 20 percent
of the body surface.
Do you concur?
I concur.
Let's get him up to Pediatrics.
Nurse Hopp
to the Nurses' station south.
Hello, Brenda.
Hi, Dr. Conners.
You need to sign these.
Thank you.
Do you notice anything
different about me, Doctor?
- You got your braces off!
- Yeah!
Come here. Let me see.
I've been trying
to show you all night!
Wow. Good job.
Yeah?
so, did it hurt
when they took them off?
Mine felt so weird after.
Mm, I keep rubbing my tongue
over them.
I can't stop.
They're so slippery.
It feels good, though,
doesn't it?
Yeah, it feels incredible.
Oh, my.
I'm... I'm sorry.
Dr. Conners to the ER.
shouldn't you go?
No. No, no.
They have a staff doctor
in the emergency ward.
We'll be fine.
What if he's in surgery?
Do you really think
I have to go?
Oh. In here, Dr. Conners.
Gentlemen, what, uh...
what seems to be the problem?
Bicycle accident.
Fractured tibia about
five inches below the patella.
Hmm.
- Dr. Harris.
- Yes?
Do you concur?
C... Concur with what, sir?
With what Dr. Ashland just said.
Do you... Do you concur?
Uh... well, it was
a bicycle accident.
Um, the boy told us.
so you concur?
Concur? Uh...
I think we should take an X ray
then stitch him up
and put him in a walking cast.
That's very good, Dr. Ashland.
Very good.
Well, you don't seem
to have much need for me.
Carry on.
I blew it, didn't I?
Why didn't I concur?
Dr. Henning, call extension 219.
Dr. Henning, extension 219.
Make yourself at home!
Frank Abagnale sr.
You're not a cop.
special Agent Hanratty, FBI.
My landlord said
you were not a cop.
Well, if you're going
to arrest me
I'd like
to put on a different suit
if that's okay with you.
No, no, I'm not here
to arrest you.
I'm looking for your son.
He's in trouble.
Do you know where he is?
If I tell you where he is
will you promise
not to tell his mother?
sure.
Frank made up a fake I.D.
and enlisted
in the Marine Corps.
He's over in Vietnam right now.
That kid is halfway
around the world
crawling through the damn jungle
fighting the Communists, so...
please, don't come to my home
and call my boy a criminal
because that kid has
more guts...
I never said he was a criminal,
Mr. Abagnale.
I said he was in trouble.
If you'd like to give me a call
and talk, here's my number.
You're not a father, are you?
Pardon me?
If you were a father,
you'd know.
I would never give up my son.
Yes, sir. I understand.
sean, sean, now get this:
"Riverbend Apartments
415 Landover, Atlanta, Georgia."
Atlanta, Georgia.
Yeah, I'm on my way
to the airport.
I'll meet the team in, uh,
in four hours.
Bye-bye.
Come on, it's okay.
You don't have to cry.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, Frank.
I can't do this.
Brenda, listen to me.
I don't care if you're
a virgin, all right?
Really, I can wait.
I'm not a virgin.
I had an abortion two years ago.
My parents had a friend do it
a man that my father
plays golf with.
And then, when I got better,
they kicked me out of the house.
I had an abortion and I wasn't
their daughter anymore.
Hey...
I'm so sorry.
Please don't be mad at me.
Please, please,
don't be mad at me.
No, no.
Please don't be mad at me.
shh. Now... what if...
what if I spoke
to your parents, right?
May-Maybe I can
straighten things out, huh?
Well, I ask them all the time
but they said I still
can't come home.
And my daddy's... a lawyer.
Aw...
Brenda...
what if you were engaged
to a doctor?
Will that change anything?
What?
What if I went
to your parents...
and I spoke to your father...
and I asked permission
to marry you?
It's empty.
Nobody here.
Dr. Conners, are you Lutheran?
Yes, I-I am a Lutheran,
but, please, call me Frank.
Frank, would you like
to say grace?
Unless you're not comfortable.
Absolutely.
Two little mice fell
into a bucket of cream.
The first mouse quickly
gave up and drowned
but the second mouse,
he struggled so hard
that he eventually churned
that cream into butter
and he walked out.
- Amen.
Amen. Oh, that was beautiful.
The mouse, he churned
that cream into butter.
That's right.
That's pretty good.
Thank you.
Frank, have you decided
which hospital
you want to work at
here in New Orleans?
Well, um, to be quite honest
I'm thinking
about getting back into law.
Oh, my!
Are you a doctor or a lawyer?
Before I went to medical school,
I passed the bar in California.
I practiced law for one year
then I decided why not
try my hand at pediatrics?
You're just full of surprises.
Yeah.
Oh, my.
A doctor and a lawyer.
Well, I'd say that Brenda
hit the jackpot.
Where did you go to law school?
Uh, Berkeley.
Berkley, Berkley. Oh, my gosh.
Isn't that where you went,
Daddy?
Maybe Frank could come work
for you, Roger.
You're always saying
how hard it is
to find
Assistant Prosecutors.
Could he, Daddy?
Could he, please?
Could he come work with you,
please?
Was that snake Hollingsworth
still teaching there
when you went through Berkley?
Hollingsworth.
Yes. Grumpy old Hollingsworth,
right?
I tell you. Meaner than ever.
And that dog of his?
Tell me, Frank, what was
the name of his little dog?
I'm sorry. Uh...
The dog was dead.
How unfortunate.
Yeah.
A doctor, a lawyer,
a Lutheran...
so what are you, Frank?
'Cause I think you're
about to ask
for my daughter's hand
in marriage
and I have a right to know.
Know what, sir?
The truth.
Tell me the truth, Frank.
What are you doing here?
What is a man like you doing
with Brenda?
If you want my blessing
if you want my daughter
I'd like to hear it
from you now.
The truth is, sir, that...
The truth is that...
I'm not a doctor,
I'm not a lawyer...
I'm not an airline pilot.
I'm... I'm nothing, really.
I'm-I'm-I'm just a kid who's
in love with your daughter.
No.
You know what you are?
You're a romantic.
Men like us are nothing
without the women we love.
I must confess, I'm guilty
of the same foolish whimsy.
I proposed to Carol
after five dates
with two nickels in my pockets
and holes in my shoes
because I knew she was the one.
so go ahead, Frank.
Don't be afraid.
Ask the question you came here
to ask me.
sir, uh, uh...
w-what would I have to do
to take the bar
here in New Orleans?
No, the... the other question.
Right through that door.
Good luck, Mr. Conners.
Thank you.
Hey, Frank...
you know what I could
never figure out?
How did you cheat on the
bar exam in Louisiana?
Why? What's the difference?
someone else took the test
for you, didn't they?
Carl, I'm going to prison
for a long time.
seriously,
what's the difference?
It's a simple question.
Are you going to eat
that eclair?
Yeah. I'm saving it for later.
Well, you want
to split it with me?
No.
Give me half that eclair
and I'll tell you.
I'm going to figure it out
sooner or later.
You'll be working under
Phillip Rigby in corporate law.
Why don't you settle in,
organize your desk?
Thank you.
We're having lunch at 12:30
with the Attorney General
and Governor McKeithen.
Himself.
The Governor.
Did we spell it right?
You sure did.
Congratulations.
Thank you, sir.
Welcome aboard.
Now...
Look at this photograph,
Mr. Stewart.
It's a photograph
of Prentice York
where they found him, dead.
Now, here is an enlargement
of part of that photograph.
This is a photograph
of the defendant's signature
on a canceled check.
Now, here is an enlargement
of that same signature
which matches
the signature on the letters
that he wrote to Mrs. Simon
which discuss the possibility
of defrauding
the great state of Louisiana.
Your Honor,
ladies and gentlemen of the jury
this is irrefutable evidence
that the defendant is,
in fact, lying.
Mr. Conners, this is
a preliminary hearing.
There is no... defendant.
There is no... jury.
It's just me.
son...
what in the hell is wrong
with you?!
- Is that Mitch?
Roger! It's Mitch!
Oh, my,
I lost all track of time.
As studio guests
for the sing-along tonight
we have the children's choir
of st. Monica's Church
in New York City.
Won't you join them and the gang
in a few songs for the Irish?
Everybody!
Has anybody here seen Kelly?
K, E, double L, Y
Have you seen him smile?
sure his hair is red,
and his eyes are blue
And he's Irish
through and through
Has anybody here seen Kelly
Kelly from the Emerald Isle?
Has anybody here seen Kelly?
K, E, double L, Y
Have you seen him smile?
sure his hair is red,
and his eyes are blue
And he's Irish
through and through
Has anybody here
seen Kelly...
Embrace me
My sweet embraceable you
You irreplaceable you
Just one look at you
My heart grew tipsy in me
You and you alone
Bring out the gypsy in me
I love all
The many charms about you
Above all
I want my arms about you...
ad.
...Don't be
a naughty baby...
What are you doing here?
I... I-I came to see you.
...My sweet embraceable...
What are you doing
dressed like this?
I took a job. A government job.
You see what I'm doing?
Do you have a good lawyer?
Well... I sort of
am a lawyer now.
Look at this letter.
The IRs wants more.
I had a deal with them:
two penalties.
They ate the cake,
now they want the crumbs.
I want to sue them.
Now they want the crumbs.
They... Here, sit down.
They're trying to scare me,
intimidate me.
You know what?
I'll make them chase me...
for the rest of their lives.
Hey, it's great
to see you, Daddy.
Listen, sit down, I...
I want to show you something.
I came here to give you this.
It's an invitation
to an engagement party.
Daddy, I'm getting married.
Can you believe that?
I'm getting married.
You don't need to worry
about anything now, Dad.
Listen, I'm getting
a brand-new Cadillac.
I'm getting a $60,000 house.
I'm-I'm getting it all back.
All-All the jewelry,
all the furs, everything, Dad.
Everything they took from us,
I'm going to get it back.
Now...
has Ma seen you
dressed like this?
Yeah, she came
to pick up some boxes.
That's okay, that's okay,
you know why?
'Cause she... she's going
to the wedding with us.
I'm going to get you
a brand-new suit, Dad.
I'm getting you
a brand-new suit.
One of those Manhattan Eagle,
three-button, black pearl suits.
You'll look great.
Those are nice. Yeah.
she won't see me.
Well, have you tried
to call her?
Uh-uh.
Why don't... why don't you
call her right now?
Dad, why don't you
call her right now? Here.
Dad, just call her.
Call her for me.
You call her, and you tell her
I have two first-class tickets
to go see her son's wedding...
Your mother's married now,
to my friend Jack Barnes.
They have a house
in Long Island.
I had an FBI agent come see me.
You got their number, son.
The guy looked scared.
The United states government,
champ, running for the hills.
Pow! To the moon!
Dad... it's over.
I'm going to stop now.
But y-you've...
They're never going
to catch you, Frank.
- Dad, she wouldn't do that.
- Why won't you sit down?
- Why would she do that to you?
- Come on, sit.
Come on, sit with me.
Have a drink.
I'm your father.
Then ask me to stop.
You can't stop.
Where are you going?
Come on, Frank,
where are you going?
Where are you going?
Where are you going tonight?
someplace exotic?
Tahiti, Hawaii?
This is Hanratty.
Hello, Carl.
Merry Christmas.
How are you, Dr. Conners?
Carl, I haven't been Dr. Conners
for months now.
Well... I'm sitting here
in my office on Christmas Eve.
What do you want?
Okay.
I want it to be over.
Uh... I want it to be over.
I'm getting married.
You know, I'm settling down.
You've stolen almost $4 million.
You think we can just
call that a wedding present?
Nah, this isn't something you
get to walk away from, Frank.
I want to call a truce.
No truce.
You will be caught,
you will go to prison.
Where did you think
this was going?
Please leave me alone, Carl.
Please?
I'm getting close, aren't I?
You're scared because
I'm getting close.
I know you... you rented
that car in shreveport
and you stayed in that hotel
on Lake Charles.
You want to run, be my guest.
Your checks don't lie
as well as you do.
stop chasing me.
I can't stop.
It's my job.
It's okay, Carl.
I just thought I'd ask,
you know?
Hey. Merry Christmas, huh?
I love my job.
All right...
let's get every newspaper
we can
every newspaper in Louisiana
for the last two months.
What are we looking for?
Engagement announcements,
name of Conners.
Conners?! Come on, Carl,
the kid would've
changed his name by now.
Mm-mm. He can't change it.
she thinks he's Conners.
If he loses the name,
he loses the girl.
I can't give you anything
But love, baby
That's the only thing
I have plenty of
Baby
Dreamin' a while,
schemin' a while...
- Congratulations.
- You having a good time?
...You're sure to find
- Happiness, and I guess
- Keep dancing, huh?
All those things
you've always pined for...
- Oh.
- Hi.
Oh, me too. Thank you.
I'm going to, uh,
the little boys' room.
- Okay.
Hurry back.
Good evening.
I'm Agent Hanratty
with the FBI.
We'd like to have
a few quiet words
with your host, if possible.
I'll get him.
Right over there, sir.
- Hi, Roger. How are you?
- Hi, Vin.
Good evening, gentlemen.
I'm Roger strong.
Carl Hanratty, FBI.
This is Agents Amdursky and Fox.
sorry to crash your party, sir.
Not at all.
What can I do for you?
If it's not too much trouble,
I'd like to meet the groom.
Is there a problem?
- Frank! Frank!
Can you hold all these?
Yeah. Come here.
They're checks.
They're from my dad's friends.
They're for us, so we can
start a new life... Hey!
What are you doing?
What's wrong?
We have to leave.
What?!
Brenda, you love me, right?
Yes.
I mean, you'd love me
no matter what.
Yes.
I mean, you'd love me
whether I was sick
or whether I was poor
or even if I had
a different name.
Frank, where'd you get
all that money?
Brenda, listen. A name, right?
A name, it doesn't matter.
My name is Frank Conners, right?
- That's who I am with you.
- Yes.
But-but we all have secrets.
You know,
sometimes when I travel
I use the name Frank Taylor.
That-That's my secret.
- Frank Taylor?!
- Yeah, Frank Taylor, you know?
- Frank Black.
- Frank Black?!
Yeah, it doesn't matter.
Why are you saying all this?
Brenda... Brenda, I don't want
to lie to you anymore.
All right? I'm not a doctor.
I never went to medical school.
I'm not a lawyer or a Harvard
graduate or a Lutheran.
Brenda, I ran away from home
a year and a half ago
when I was 16.
Frank...
Frank?
You're not a Lutheran?
Brenda... you see
all this money?
You see all this money?
I have more.
I have plenty more.
I have enough money
to last us
for the rest of our lives
- Look.
Frank, stop teasing me.
You're Frank Conners.
You're Frank Conners,
and you're 2: years old and...
Brenda...
Why would you lie to me?
- Brenda, Brenda...
- I want to know your name.
- Listen to me, Brenda.
- Tell me your name.
We can live anywhere we want
but you have to trust me,
Brenda.
- Do you trust me?
- Yes.
- Do you love me, Brenda?
- You love me?
- I love you.
Excuse me, Mother.
Honey, this is Mr. Hanratty.
My wife Carol.
- Oh, Mister...?
- Hanratty, ma'am.
- Ratty.
- Yes.
Have you seen Frank or Brenda?
I-I think they went upstairs.
Frank...
:
Brenda, come here.
Okay, in two days,
you're going to meet me
at Miami International
Airport, all right?
You're going to leave the house
after your parents go to sleep.
You're going to take a taxicab.
You give the taxi driver
this money right here
and you tell him to drive
all through the night.
Brenda, you're going
to leave at 10:00am.
- 10:00am, all right?
- But...
I never stop
Till I get to the top...
Which room, sir?
In the corner.
You have to listen to me,
all right?
The International Terminal
in Miami, all right? Say it.
Okay, the International
Terminal in Miami.
- No matter what...
- You're going to take a taxicab.
- I will take a taxi.
You're going to be there
at 10:00am.
I will be there at 10:00am,
no matter what.
- In two days.
- Two days.
Two days, Brenda. Two days.
In two days, I'll be there
no matter what, at 10:00am.
You're not going
to tell anyone, Brenda.
You have to promise me, now.
Frank, please!
Before you go,
please tell me your name.
Please, tell me.
Frank William Abagnale Jr.
National Airlines
flight number 27, serving
Fort Myers, sarasota, Tampa
and New York Kennedy,
is now available at gate n...
skycap, Gate 14.
Taxi!
Your attention...
Brenda.
This guy's a no-show.
He must've got wise to us.
Maybe he was tipped.
If he's not here today,
he'll be tomorrow.
We'll get him before
he leaves the country.
He doesn't have a passport.
For the last six months, he's
gone to Harvard and Berkeley.
I'm betting he can get
a passport.
so we have all our men
waiting for him here
in Miami International.
He's used it before.
He knows the layout.
I talked to Miami police;
they've offered us
50 uniformed cops
in two shifts of 25.
With our guys, that's almost
100 men in one airport.
Don't you think
we should spread it around?
No, no, this is the exit point.
Well, how do you know
he hasn't rented a car
and driven to airports
in New York, Atlanta?
Because I'm not in New York.
I'm not in Atlanta.
Yes, this is, uh, Frank Roberts
and I'm letting
all the universities
in the area know
that Pan Am will be initiating
a new recruiting program
this year.
I'II, uh, be stopping
by your campus tomorrow morning.
Thank you all very much
for coming.
At the end of the day
I'll be choosing eight
young ladies to be a part of...
...Pan Am's future stewardess
flight crew program.
Now, these eight young ladies
will accompany me
on a two-month public relations
tour through Europe.
They will discover firsthand
what it takes
to be a Pan American stewardess.
Give me at least two men...
Nah, one man
per every two counters.
- Mm-hmm.
- All right?
Amdursky?
Yeah?
Make sure your uniforms
are covering
the sidewalk entrances
and exits.
Hey... let's have, uh, periodic
sweeps of the men's lav.
You, here.
What qualifies me
to be a future stewardess?
Well, I think
that I'm really friendly
and I can really help out
and, um, make people
feel welcome on the plane and...
We'll be traveling
at 6,000 miles per hour
at an altitude of 300 feet.
All my bags are packed,
I'm ready to go...
Ilene Anderson.
Miggy Acker.
Debra Jo McMillan.
Candy Heston.
Come fly with me,
let's fly, let's fly away
If you can use
some exotic booze
There's a bar in far Bombay
Come fly with me,
let's fly, let's fly away
let's float down to Peru
In Ilama land
there's a one-man band
And he'll toot his flute
for you
Come fly with me...
Hi.
...Let's take off
in the blue
Once I get you up there
Where the air is rarefied
We'll just glide starry-eyed
Once I get you up there...
You see that blonde out front?
I should have been a pilot.
Exactly.
Mr. Carl Hanratty
please pick up
the courtesy telephone.
Hanratty.
Carl, your walkie-talkie
wasn't working.
There's a guy
in a Pan Am uniform
sitting in a white Coupe DeVille
out in front of Terminal J.
That's the charter terminal.
Can you get a look at his face?
He's got his pilot's cap on.
Carl, I think it's him!
...Just say the words,
and we'll beat the birds
Down to Acapulco Bay...
Watch out, watch out,
watch out!
...It's perfect for a flying
honeymoon, they say...
Out of the car, Frank.
Frank?!
step out of the car!
Keep your hands
where I can see 'em.
Don't shoot me!
I'm just a driver.
A man paid me $100
to wear this uniform
and pick someone up
at the airport.
Who you picking up?
Hey!
Pack up, let's fly away.
South America, Australia
Singapore, Egypt.
The kid's gone
completely out of control.
Why wasn't I called?
Nobody was called, sir.
The banks didn't know what
was happening till last week.
That's impossible.
They didn't call
'cause it's not counterfeiting.
- It's something else.
- Well, what is he doing?
He's making real checks, sir.
These are so perfect
the airline didn't know
the difference.
Last check was cashed
in Madrid a week ago.
My guess is he's still there.
We have to leave now, sir.
Today.
Go where?
spain? You want to go to spain?
Well, eventually,
he's got to go back
to where the checks
were printed.
I think that's why
he's moving back through Europe.
Look at the map, sir.
He's making a circle.
He's running out of checks.
I know it's a...
it's a long shot, sir
but if we track him from Madrid,
sir, we could still catch him.
I'm sorry, Carl,
if you couldn't catch him here
you're not going
to catch him there.
But, sir, we're going
to let him get away.
No, Carl, you let him get away.
A perfect one-16th
all the way around.
Hmm!
Color separation is flawless.
There's no bleeding. Hmm.
Nobody does work like this
in the states.
Nobody but us.
Where was it printed?
It was printed on a monster...
A monster.
...a Heidelberg, an Istra...
Heidelberg.
...a dinosaur, four colors.
You can smell the weight.
Two tons, without the ink.
Where do they do printing
like this?
Germany, Great Britain...
France.
France!
France. Frank's mother said
the name of a village in France
where they didn't have sara Lee.
The village where
she met Frank's father.
Oh, yeah,
I don't remember, uh...
It started with an M.
It was, uh, "Mont" something.
"Mont." Mr. Fox?
Uh, yes, yes.
Question: "You met your husband
during the war?"
"Yes, I lived
in a small village in France.
Yeah, right.
"The kind of place where
they never heard of sara Lee."
Tell me you wrote down the name
of the village, Mr. Fox.
Montrichard.
Laeti triumphantes
Venite, venite
In Bethlehem
Natum videte
Regem angelorum
Venite adoremus,
Venite adoremus
Venite...
Carl?
Carl!
Merry Christmas!
How is it that we're always
talking on Christmas, Carl?
Every Christmas
I'm talking to you!
Put your shirt on, Frank.
You're under arrest.
Hey, are you hungry?
Do you want some beans, Carl?
They got the best
French beans here.
Here, give these a try.
There's two dozen French
police officers outside.
Carl, I gotta tell you,
they're delicious.
They wanted to bring you in.
You want a bite?
But they needed the help
of an American.
Are you hungry?
You want a bite?
But I told them
I wouldn't bring them to you
unless I could put the cuffs
on you myself.
Well, you have a gun?
You have a gun?
- No gun?
- No.
No gun.
And-and you're...
and you're telling me what?
There's, uh,
there's uh...
there's two dozen
French police officers out there
right now on Christmas Eve?
That's what you're telling me?
Yeah.
All right, all right.
Well, there's no windows here.
I'm going to take a look
out the front door.
No! No!
I told them I'd walk out first
and give a signal.
Here, you can
put these on yourself.
No, I can't do that!
I can't do that.
You know why?
'Cause I think
you're full of shit.
I don't... I don't think
there's anyone else out there.
I think... I think
it's just me and you.
That's right.
I think it's just me and you,
and you know what?
You're going to have
to catch me yourself!
I wo... we don't have time
for this.
Ah, that's good. That's good.
Tell me what you want me to see,
huh?
I wouldn't lie to you.
Look, you're wearing
a wedding ring.
You're wearing
a wedding ring, Carl!
You lied to me about that!
Didn't you lie about that?!
You asked me if I had a family.
I did, but I don't anymore.
Yes? No, no, no,
there is no problem.
We're coming out right now.
Whoa, that was good.
That was good.
What, did you...
you pay some hotel desk clerk
to make that call for you,
is that what you did?
It was Captain Luc.
I've got one minute
to bring you out.
Captain Luc? Captain Luc!
Ooh, Captain Luc.
Well, Carl, I gotta say
that-that sounds
pretty official to me
but like I said, I...
I think it's just
me and you here,
it's me and you.
so you're going to have
to catch me.
Frank. Frank!
You have to trust me on this!
These people
have been embarrassed, Frank.
They're angry.
You rob their banks,
you steal their money
you live in their country.
I told you this was
what was going to happen
that there was no other way
for it to end.
Don't make a mistake!
That's good.
That's good, Carl, you know?
Keep pushing that lie.
Keep pushing it.
Keep pushing
till you make it true.
They're going to kill you!
You walk out that door,
they're going to kill you.
Is that the truth?
Yeah.
You have any children, Carl?
I have a four-year-old daughter.
You swear on your daughter?
You swear?
Redit ce chant melodieux
Gloria
In excelsius Deo
Gloria...
That was really good, Carl.
I have him in custody.
I got him.
I got him! It's all right!
It's all right!
I got him!
Hey, I want it...
I want it on the record.
Frank Abagnale surrendered
of his own accord.
Understood? Understood?
Where are you taking him?
I'm... I'm supposed to go.
Let me in the...
Let me in the car!
Hey! Let me in the car!
Gloria...
Don't worry, Frank!
I'll have you extradited
back to the United states.
Don't worry.
Gloria
In excelsius Deo.
Carl...
Carl, you have to remember
to let me call my father
when we land.
I just want to,
I want to talk to him
before he sees me on television
or something like that.
Carl, look.
That's LaGuardia right there.
Runway 4-4.
Frank, your father is dead.
I'm sorry.
I didn't want to say anything
till we got closer to home.
He-He... He fell down some steps
at Grand Central station
trying to catch a train.
I didn't want to be the one
to tell you.
You're lying, right?
You said I could talk to him.
Carl, who are you to...
who are you to say
something like that, huh?
Who are you
to say something like that?
You said I could talk to him.
He fell, and he...
and he broke his neck.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
Goddamn it!
Carl, I'm going to be sick!
- It's all right.
It's all right. It's okay.
Carl, I got to go
to the bathroom.
I'm going to be sick.
sure.
Let's go in the bathroom.
Goddamn it!
Oh, Daddy...
You'll have take your seat, sir.
I've told you twice.
We're landing.
- Sorry. Thank you...
- All of you.
Frank! Come on now.
- Frank?
- We're landing in six minutes.
All of you need to be
in your seats
- With your seat belts fastened.
- Frank, open the door!
Frank!
- You do it.
- Yeah.
Frank! Frank!
All right, remain seated,
everyone, please.
FBI. Stay seated.
- Please remain seated!
- Stay seated.
You must stay seated
until the aircraft
has come to a complete stop.
God almighty.
Chestnuts roasting
on an open fire...
Jack Frost nipping
at your nose
Yuletide carols
being sung by a choir
And folks dressed up
like Eskimos
Everybody knows
A turkey and some mistletoe
Help to make
the season bright
Tiny tots with their eyes
all aglow
Will find it hard
to sleep tonight...
What's your name?
They know that santa's
on his way...
Where's your mommy?
...He's loaded lots of toys
and goodies on his sleigh
And every mother's child
is gonna spy
To see if reindeer
really know how to fly...
And so I'm offering
this simple phrase...
To kids from one to 92
Although it's been said
many times
Many ways:
"Merry Christmas..."
Hands behind your head!
...To you.
Carl, get me in the car,
please.
Get me in the car.
Put him in.
Taking into account
the gravity of these crimes
your history of bold
and elusive behavior
and your complete lack
of respect
for the laws
of the United States
I have no choice
but to ignore your request
to be treated as a minor
and sentence you to 12 years
in Atlanta's
maximum security prison
and recommend strongly
that you be kept in isolation
for the entirety
of that sentence.
..."Merry Christmas to you."
Use that door over there.
...and give everyone my love.
I think about them all the time.
Merry Christmas, Frank.
Hey, I got you
some comic books here.
How's your daughter?
What was her name?
Grace.
Well... I don't know.
she lives with her mother
in Chicago
and I don't get to see her much.
What's in the briefcase?
Oh. I'm on my way
to the airport.
It's a paperhanger
who's working his way
through Minnesota.
Aw, geez, he's...
he's driving us crazy.
You got any of the checks?
Yeah, yeah, I got a...
a counterfeit that he drew
on the Great Lakes
savings and Loan.
see, he's just using
a stencil machine
and an Underwood.
Yeah, it's a teller at the bank.
say again?
I-It's definitely a teller,
Carl.
I mean, banks,
they always use hand-stamps
for the dates, see.
They get used
over and over again
so they always get worn out
and the numbers
are always cracking.
The sixes and the nines...
see, they go first.
Thanks.
I'd like you to take a look
at something for me.
Tell me what you think.
That's a fake.
How do you know?
You haven't looked at it.
Well, there's
no perforated edge, right?
I mean, this... this check
was hand-cut, not fed.
Yeah...
Paper is double-bonded
much too heavy
to be a bank check.
Magnetic ink, it's, uh,
raised against my fingers
instead of flat.
And this doesn't smell
like MICR.
It's some kind of a...
you know,
some kind of a drafting ink.
You know, the kind you get
at a stationery store.
Frank...
would you be interested
in working
with the FBI's
Financial Crimes Unit?
I already got a job here.
You know, I, uh,
deliver the mail.
Frank, we have the power
to take you out of prison.
You'd be placed
in the custody of the FBI
where you'd serve out
the remainder of your sentence
as an employee
of the federal government.
Under whose custody?
Hi. I-I'm Frank Abagnale.
I'm supposed to start work
here today.
It's a tour company
operating out of the BVI.
sir, Mr. Abagnale is here.
I'm going to call you back.
Hello, Carl.
Welcome to the FBI.
I'll show you
where you're working.
Carl... how long
do I have to work here?
It's: :15 in the morning
to 5:00 in the afternoon.
45 minutes for lunch.
No, I...
I mean, how long?
Every day.
Every day, Frank,
till we let you go.
- Yeah.
- Hey, Carl.
- Hi.
How you doing?
It's not a good time, Frank.
I'm clearing my desk
for the weekend.
Carl, you mind if I come
to work with you tomorrow?
Tomorrow is saturday.
I'm flying to Chicago
to see my daughter.
I'll be back to work on Monday.
You're going to see Grace, huh?
Well, that's the plan.
so what should I do till Monday?
I'm sorry, kid,
I can't help you there.
Excuse me.
This is Hanratty.
Oh, yeah, put him on.
Mr. Sawyer.
How are you?
I have a half a dozen
more checks
on that tour operator
at the BVI.
American Airlines 355
serving Chicago
and san Francisco
is now open
for passenger check-in.
How'd you do it, Frank?
How'd you pass the bar
in Louisiana?
What are you doing here?
Listen...
I'm sorry I put you
through all this.
You go back to Europe, you're
gonna die in Perpignan Prison.
You try to run
here in the states
we'll send you
back to Atlanta for 50 years.
I know that.
I spent four years trying
to arrange your release.
Had to convince my bosses
at the FBI
and the Attorney General
of the United states
you wouldn't run.
Why'd you do it?
You're just a kid.
I'm not your kid.
You said you were
going to Chicago.
My daughter can't see me
this weekend.
she's going skiing.
You said she was four years old.
You're lying.
she was four when I left.
Now she's 15.
My wife's been remarried
for 11 years.
I see Grace every now and again.
I don't understand.
sure you do.
sometimes it's easier
living the lie.
I'm going to let you
fly tonight, Frank.
I'm not even going
to try to stop you.
That's 'cause I know
you'll be back on Monday.
Yeah? How do you know
I'll come back?
Look.
Frank...
nobody's chasing you.
American Airlines flight 131
to Pittsburgh
is now ready for boarding.
Passengers with boarding passes,
please proceed to Gate 23A.
Okay.
Alice, has he still not called?
No, he hasn't.
Good morning.
I've, uh, called this meeting
to discuss
a new type of check fraud
and counterfeiting
which the unsub is washing
and altering checks
then passing them
throughout Arizona.
This unsub is a big dog
passing checks
as large as five figures.
sorry I'm late.
sorry.
We have a recovered check
on Agent Reiter's desk.
Why don't we step out
to the bullpen?
There's impressions
on every line.
Looks like the original amount
was for $60.
Mind if I take a look?
Cashed in Flagstaff a week ago.
Cost the bank $16,000.
It's a real check.
Yeah.
Yeah. It's been washed.
The only thing original
is the signature.
But it's perfect, Carl.
I mean...
I mean, this isn't hydrochloride
or bleach.
No.
something new.
Maybe a nail polish remover
where the acetone
removes the ink
that's not been printed?
How did you do it, Frank?
How did you cheat
on the bar exam in Louisiana?
I didn't cheat.
I studied for two weeks
and I passed.
Is that the truth, Frank?
Is that the truth?
I'll bet this guy steals checks
out of mailboxes.
He washes off their names
and he puts on his own.
You're saying that he's a local?
Well, if it were me, you know
I'd call the bank first,
I'd check out the balance...
Make sure there's enough money
in there
to make it worth your while.
Exactly.
You know, Carl, I think
this guy's pretty smart.
I guess all we have to do now
is catch him.
We'll start first thing
in the morning.
We'll run the name
Eric Anthony Feeders.
In Nevada, Arizona, California.
Both names, right?
Chris Frank, too?
Yeah...
sync by
지노
jin5a@naver.com
레오나르도 디카프리오
톰 행크스
캐치미 이프 유 캔
크리스토퍼 월큰
음악 : 존 윌리엄스
감독 : 스티븐 스필버그
실화를 바탕으로 한 이야기
" 진실말하기"에 오신 걸 환영 합니다
첫 번째 손님은 우리가 이 쇼에서
결코 만나보지 못했던
아주 놀라운 경력의 소유자입니다
제 말이 무슨 뜻인지는
곧 알게 될 겁니다
1 번, 당신 이름은 뭐죠?
제 이름은 프랭크 윌리엄 아백내일입니다
2 번?
3 번?
제 이름은 프랭크 윌리엄 아백내일입니다
1964 년부터 1967년까지
팬암항공의 조종사로
성공적으로 위장 했습니다
그리고 2백만 마일 이상을
공짜로 비행 했습니다
그 동안에 조지아 병원의
소아과 레지던트 치프 이면서
루이지애나주의 법무장관보로
일했습니다
제가 잡혔을 때
미국 역사상 가장 어리면서
대담한 위조범으로
여겨졌습니다
가짜수표로 거의 400만 달러를
현금화 했습니다
26 개의 나라에서
그리고 50개의 모든 주에서
이 모든 걸 19살 생일이
되기 전에 했습니다
제 이름은
프랭크 윌리엄 아백내일입니다
이제 처음으로
그가 진실을 말하겠군요
키티부터 먼저 질문 하겠습니다
고마워요
1 번, 당신은 재능도 많고
아주 영리한 청년인 것 같은데
왜 합법적인 직업을
가지지 않았나요?
이건 분명 돈 문제에요
전 어렸을 때 돈이 필요했고
이게 가장 쉬운
방법 이었습니다
2 번, 이 모든게 아주
멋진 것 같은데
마침내 누가 당신을 잡았나요?
그의 이름은 칼 핸래티였습니다
핸래티
칼 핸드래티
전 칼 핸래티입니다
미국에서 온 FBI입니다
미국 죄수인 아백내일을
인수받도록 명령 받았습니다
1969년, 크리스마스이브
마르세이유, 프랑스
여기 앉으시죠
저 문은 열지 마세요
이 구멍으로
아무것도 넣지 마세요
아...대단하군
나도 약간 감기에 걸렸어
프랭크
인권에 따라 유럽에서 잡혔을 때의
인도 조항을 읽을 필요가 있어
1 번 조항
인도 전에는 법에 따라
처벌 가능하고
최고 1년까지 그곳에서
감금할 수 있다
도와줘요
프랭크
멈춰
도와줘요
날 바보로 만들지 마
아직 16페이지 남았어
기다려
2 번 조항
만약 처벌 가능한 범죄에 대한
인도가 요구된다면...
프랭크
프랭크?
젠장...
여기 문 열어봐요
의사가 필요해요
네
의사!! 당장!
식은땀 흘리지 마, 프랭크
의사한테 데려다 줄게
프랭크, 내 말 들리면
걱정하지 마라
내일 아침에 집으로 데려갈게
내일 아침에 집이다, 프랭크
뭐하는 겁니까?
이를 씻어 내는 겁니다
이 남자는 미국에 가는
비행기를 탈 겁니다
의사를 봐야 돼요
의사는 내일 올 겁니다
난 권한이 있어요
날 무시하기에는
너무 오래 기다렸어요
만약 그가 죽으면
당신 책임입니다
이런 프랭크...
좋아요, 칼
집에 가요
뉴로셀 로터리클럽은
1919년에 세워졌습니다
그 긴 시간동안
소수의 가치 있는 신사들만이
평생회원이 되었습니다
명예의 벽에 있는57명의
이름을 보는 건 영광입니다
오늘밤 우린 58번째를 만듭니다
제 좋은 친구를 소개해 드리니
모두 일어서 주십시요
언제나 준비가 되어 있는 남자인...
프랭크 윌리엄 아백내일
6년전
1963년
뉴욕, 뉴로셀
로버트 웨그너 시장님과 함께
여기 서 있는 것이 영광입니다
그리고 우리 클럽
회장이신 잭 반스...
무엇보다도 제 사랑하는 아내인
폴라를 볼 수 있어서 영광입니다
그리고 제 아들
프랭크 주니어
앞줄에 앉아 있죠
작은 생쥐 두마리가
크림 바구니에 빠졌습니다
첫 번째 생쥐는 빨리 포기하고
익사했습니다
두 번째 생쥐는 그만두지 않았습니다
계속 휘우적거리다...
결국, 크림을 버터로 만들었습니다
그리고 기어 나왔죠
신사 여러분, 전 이제부터
그 두 번째 생쥐입니다
넌 아빠보다 춤을
잘 추는구나, 프랭키
들으셨죠? 아빠
웃기는군
여자는 춤을 알지
우리가 만났을 때 추었던
춤을 보여줘
기억할 수가 없어요
그 작은 프랑스 마을 사람들은
미국인들을 보게 된 걸
행복해 했지
우리를 위해서 쇼를 준비했어
그래서 200명의 군인들을...
그 얘기는 알아요, 아빠
그 작은 홀에 밀어 넣었지
무대 위로 처음 올라온 소녀가
바로 네 엄마였다
그녀는 춤추기 시작했어
우린 여자를 못 본지
몇 달 이나 됐었지
그런데 여기 금발에
천사 같은...
금발의 쇼걸
남자들은 말 그대로
숨을 멈췄어
엄마를 위해 숨을 멈췄대요
들었어요?
떠나야 했을 때
난 멈춰버렸어
난 그녀 없이는 프랑스를
떠나지 않겠다
- 그리고 안 그랬지
- 안 그랬죠
오, 이런...
엄마
- 이대로 내버려 둘 순 없어
- 별일 아냐
- 프랭키, 타월 가져와라
- 네
이봐...
나하고 춤춰요, 폴라
당신하고 춤출 때마다
곤경에 빠져요
프랭크, 일어나라
어서 가자
일어나, 어서...
프랭크, 일어나
아빠...
오늘 학교 갈 필요 없다
괜찮아
눈이라도 왔어요?
검은 양복 있니?
또 늦잠을 잤어요
시내에서 오늘 중요한
회의가 있다
이거 먹어라.
어서...
부인, 열어주세요
제발 열어주세요
부인...
중요한 일입니다
무슨 일이죠?
30분 후에 열겁니다
그냥 문만 열어주세요
중요한 일입니다
미안하지만 30분후에 엽니다
이름이 뭐죠, 부인?
- 도로시
- 도로시, 예쁜 이름이군요
제가 좀 급합니다
제 아들 프랭크를 위한 양복이
한 벌 필요 합니다
검은 양복이 필요합니다
가족 중에 누가 돌아가셨어요
제 아버지가 85살인데
전쟁영웅이에요
장례식은 오늘 오후에 있어요
군사장례식인데 비행기들이
고별비행을 합니다
프랭크는 몇 시간 동안 입을
양복이 필요합니다
미안하지만 우린 빌려주진 않아요
그리고 문도 안 열었어요
도로시, 도로시
제발...돌아와요
도로시
이거 당신 건가요?
주차장에서 찾았어요
당신 목에서 미끄러졌나 봅니다
보도를 치지 마라
이제 차에서 내려서
뒤로 걸어와 문을 열어라
좋아요. 다음은 뭐죠?
좋아. 차를 여기 세우고
내가 안으로 들어가면
앞좌석에 앉아서 기다려라
경찰이 와서 딱지를 떼더라도
차를 움직이지 마라
이해하겠니?
아빠, 무엇 때문에
이러는 거죠?
양키스가 왜 언제나
이기는 줄 아니?
미키 맨틀이 있어서?
아냐. 그건 다른 팀들이
그 줄무늬 유니폼에
신경을 쓰기 때문이야
이걸 지켜봐라
체이스맨하탄 은행의 지점장이
이제 아버지를 위해서
문을 열려고 한다
아백내일씨?
우린 보통 국세청하고
문제가 있는 사람한테
돈을 빌려주지 않습니다
그건 오해입니다
사람을 잘못 고용해서
회계장부를 잘못 썼고...
누구나 할 수 있는 실수에요
난 단지 이 위기를 벗어날 수 있도록
당신들이 도와주길 바랍니다
선생님, 당신은 세금문제로
정부에서 조사를 받고 있어요
제 가게는 뉴로셀에서
대단해요
고객들은 뉴욕 전체에서 옵니다
당신은 체이스맨하탄의
고객이 아니에요
우린 당신을 모릅니다
뉴로셀로 돌아가면 되겠군요
그들은 당신을 아니까
도와줄 겁니다
제 거래은행은
이런 사업을 안해요
이런 은행들만
그런 사업을 합니다
제가 실수한 걸 압니다
제가 그랬죠
그 사람들은 냉혹해요
내 가게로 와서
감옥에 넣겠다고 위협해요
여기는 미국이에요
난 범죄자가 아니에요
뉴로셀 로타리클럽의
영광스런 평생회원이에요
제가 원하는 건 그놈들한테
이기게 도와달라는 거에요
이건 이기고 지는
문제가 아닙니다
이건 위험의 문제죠
여긴 세계 제일의
은행이에요
뭐가 걱정입니까
뭐가 위험하죠?
아빠, 왜 차를 가져가게 놔두세요?
그는 아무것도 안 가져갔다
우린 캔디를 가질거고
500달러 받았다
어서, 프랭크
양복 돌려주러 가자
여기도 좋을 거야
작지만, 일도 조금만 하면 돼
당신 집안 일이 줄 거야
안녕, 아빠
안녕
엄마는 어디 갔니?
몰라요
일자리 구하러
가신다고 했어요
그녀가 뭘 할 건데...
구두판매원?
뭐하는 거니?
팬케익 좀 드실래요?
저녁으로?
내 아들의 16살 생일날?
우린 팬케익을 먹지는 않을 거다
이봐...
그렇게 보지 마
- 내가 잊은 줄 알았구나
- 아니에요
은행계좌를 하나 만들었다
네 이름으로
네 계좌에 25달러를
넣어 두었다
원하는 건 뭐든지 사라
엄마한테는 얘기하지 말고...
안 할게요
고마워요
은행이 아빠를
배신하지 않았나요?
그래, 그들이 모두
날 배반했지
근데 왜 은행 계좌를 만드셨어요?
왜냐하면 언젠가는 네가 그들한테
대출을 받아야 하기 때문이다
집, 자동차를 사기 위해서...
그들이 모든 돈을 가지고 있다
50 개의 수표가 있다, 프랭크
무슨 뜻이냐 하면
이젠 너도 그들의 일원이다
나도 그들의 일원이라...
그들이 모든 걸 가지고 있다
제 이름이 위에 있네요
달까지...
달까지
다 왔다.
학교 일 뿐이야
웨츠번하고 다르지 않아
엄마, 끊는다고 하셨잖아요
프랭키, 여기선 교복
입을 필요없단다
자켓을 벗는 게 어떠니
버릇이 돼서 그래요
- 실례합니다
- 네?
17 호 불어반이
어딘줄 아세요?
아까 그 사이코 아냐?
꼭 대리교사처럼 생겼군
조용히 해주세요
제 이름은 아백내일입니다
아백내일이에요
아백날리도 아니고
아백낼리도 아니고
바로 아백내일입니다
지난 시간에 어디까지 했는지
말해줄 사람?
이봐, 친구들. 지금 학급 전체에
말하는 겁니다
의자에 앉아요
7 장
8 장으로 교과서를 펴 주세요
이제 시작할 겁니다
실례합니다. 이름이 뭐지?
브래드
브래드, 일어나 보지 그래
학급 전체 앞으로 나와서
대화 5번을 읽어보세요
절 보냈어요
버다 대신에 대리교사가
필요하다고 했어요
딕슨에서 여기까지 왔어요
제가 언제나 버다의
대리교사였어요
이봐, 왜 계속 안 읽지?
다시는 이 학교에 안 오겠어요
나한테 전화하지 말라고 하세요
내 나이의 사람한테
이게 쉬운 줄 알아요
여행에 든 돈은 어떡하고...
아백내일 부모님
아드님의 출석에 대한
문제가 아닙니다
이렇게 알려드리게 되서
유감이지만
지난주내내 프랭크가 글래시스 부인의
불어반을 가르쳤습니다
그가 어떻게 했다고요?
당신 아들이 대리교사인체 했어요
학생들에게 강의하고
숙제를 내주고...
글래시스 부인이 아파서
진짜 대리교사하고
혼동이 있었던 것 같습니다
당신 아들이 어제 학부모 회의를
열었어요
트린튼에 있는 프랑스빵 공장으로
야외수업을 가기로 결정 했습니다
문제가 뭔지 아시겠어요?
데븐포트 부인, 오늘 수업 빠지는
메모를 가져왔어요.
병원에 가야 돼요
잠깐만, 곧 돌아올게
이봐, 접어야 돼
뭐라고?
그 메모 가짜지?
접어야만 돼
이건 병원에 가야 된다는
엄마의 메모야
하지만 접은 자국이 없잖아
엄마가 선생님한테 주라고
메모를 주시면
처음 하는 일이 접어서
주머니에 넣는거야
그래서 접은 자국이 생기지
엄마, 저 왔어요
전에 말했던 여자애
기억 나세요
오늘 데이트하기로 했어요
둘이서 무도회에
가기로 했어요
엄마, 이거 제 면허증이에요?
그게 다에요
방 2개
프랭키
아빠 친구 기억하니?
잭 반스
클럽에
아버지를 보러 들르셨다
집안을 구경시켜 드렸다
집이 아주 넓군요, 폴라
아빠는 가게에 계세요
그래, 프랭크
점점 아버지를 닮아가는구나
샌드위치 고마워요, 폴라
- 다음에 보자
- 기다려요
아저씨 건가요?
오...고맙다. 프랭크
이게 회장 뱃지지
잃어버렸다면
아주 곤란했을 거다
나중에 보자
배고프니, 프랭키?
샌드위치 만들어 줄게
잭은 아버지하고 사업문제를
상의하려고 했어
변호사를 선임해서
정부를 고소해야 한대..
우린한테 이러는 건
불법이라고
왜 아무 말도 안 하는거니
말하지 않을거지?
그럴거니?
그거야. 말하지 마라
테니스 클럽의 친구를 만나러
몇 시간 나갔다 올게
집에 돌아와서
모두 함께 저녁 먹자
좋아?
아무 말도 안하니...
바보 같은 생각이야
그는 깔끔해
우리가 누굴 고소할 수 있겠니
돈 필요하니, 프랭키?
몇 달러로 레코드판이라도 사라
여기 5달러 가져라
끊는다고 약속했잖아요
엄마, 저 왔어요
이봐...
가까이 오지 말아요
들었어요?
누군지 모르지만
다시 여기 돌아온다면...
프랭크...
진정해라. 난 딕 케스너다
네 물건들은 여기 놓아두고
옆방으로 날 따라와라
모두 기다리고 있다
겁먹을 필요 없다, 프랭크
편지 쓸게, 프랭크
난 언제나 여기 있다
하지만 법이 있단다
이 나라에선 모든 게
법에 따라야 된단다
이제 해야 할일은 결정을
해야 되는 거야
그래서 케스너씨가 여기 온 거야
많은 경우에 이런 결정이
법정으로 가지만
그건 비용이 아주 많이 든다
양육권 싸움은...
아무도 소송을
원하지는 않아요
날 봐라, 프랭크
아무도 싸우지 않아
아빠, 무슨 일이에요?
할머니 기억나니?
에브 할머니는
오늘 아침에 오셨다
무슨 말인지
이해 하겠니,  프랭크?
엄마, 아빠는 이혼하려고 한다
아무것도 바뀌지 않아
우린 계속 만날 수 있어
그만둬요, 제발...
프랭크는 평생을 그래야 돼요
이걸 모두 읽을 필요는 없다
이건 부모님에 대한거야
지루하고...
여기 이 문구는 중요하다
이게 네가 누구하고
살지를 말 한다
이혼한 후에
누구의 보호 아래인지
그리고 여기 빈 칸이 있어
부엌으로 가서 테이블에 앉아
이름을 적어라
시간이 얼마나 오래
걸려도 좋지만
이 방으로 돌아 올 때는
빈칸을 채워 와라
프랭크, 그냥 이름을 적어
그럼 모두 끝날거야
괜찮을거다
아빠, 무슨 이름이요?
네 엄마하고 아빠...
그냥 이름을 적어
간단한거야
그렇게 겁에 질린
표정하지 마라
이건 시험이 아냐
잘못된 답이란 없다
중앙역으로 가는 표 주세요
3 달러 50센트입니다
수표를 써 드려도 되나요?
칼, 아빠한테 전화하고 싶어요
뉴욕에 도착하면
전화하게 해줄게
1969년
프랑스, 파리
몇 시간 후면 공항으로 간다
그냥 거기 앉아 있어
조용히...
칼, 이 호텔 반대편에는 공원을
볼 수 있는 스위트룸이 있어요
여기가 FBI가 얻을 수 있는
제일 좋은 방이야
괜찮아요
더 나쁜 곳에도 있었어요
만더씨, 제 말 좀 들어 보세요
네 얘기 듣고 싶지 않다
수표 2장이 돌아왔다
내가 얼마나 곤란하지 아니?
제 말 들어 주세요
은행이 실수를 한 거에요
다른 수표를 지금
바로 써 드릴게요
가만 내가 바보인줄 아니?
봐요. 지금은 한밤중이에요
제가 어디로 가겠어요
빌어먹을 아이들은
집으로 돌아가라
이해해 주세요
제 상관이 퀸즈의 브루클린으로
절 보내 놓고
이제는 롱아일랜드로 가서
고객 몇 분을 밤에
도시로 데리고 나오라는군요
미안해요
우린 다른 은행의 수표를
돈으로 바꿔주지 않아요
이게 좋은지 어떻게 알겠어요
이름이 뭐라고 했죠?
애쉴리
애쉴리, 저기 밖에서
뭘 발견했는지 아세요?
아마 당신 목에서 떨어 졌겠죠
내가 도와줄 일이라도 있나?
제 할머니 생일이 다음주라
특별히 놀래 드릴려고 해요
제발...중간고사가 다음주인데
책을 도둑  맞았어요
제발...겨우 5달러에요
아무도 알 필요 없어요
미안합니다. 하지만 우린
모르는 사람한테서
수표를 받지 않아요
돌아와 주셔서 기쁩니다
칼스기장님
어떻게 생각하나, 안젤로?
저 아가씨들 오늘 오후에
머물거네
이제 다 왔군
- 사인해 주실래요?
- 물론이지
저도 사인해 주실래요?
- 파일럿이 되고 싶니?
- 네
좋았어
여기 있다
학교에서 공부 열심히 해라
아빠에게
비행기 조종사가 되기로
결심 했어요
큰 항공사들을 다 방문했고
면접이 몇 군데 잡혀 있어요
아백내일 문구점
엄마는 어때요?
요즘 전화하셨어요?
사랑하는 아들,
프랭크로부터
팬암
안녕하세요?
전 멀로이 고등학교의
프랭크 블랙이에요
모간씨하고 약속이 있는데요
학교신문에 기사를 쓴
젊은 친구군요
네, 부인. 바로 저에요
조종사가 되기 위한
모든 방법을 알고 싶어요
팬암은 어떤 공항으로 비행하죠?
조종사는 어떻게 만들어지죠?
누가 비행하는지
누가 결정하죠?
잠깐만 한번에 하나씩
물어봐라
조종사가 다른 조종사와
붙어 있다는 게 무슨 뜻이죠?
어떤 비행기들이 있으세요?
여러가지 비행기가 있는데
DC-8, 707,
컨스틸레이션...
조종사들이 달고 있는
뱃지는 뭐죠?
조종사들은 언제나 두가지를
가지고 다니지
하나는 팬암에서 나온 이것과 같은
항공사 직원 뱃지이고
다른 하나는
연방항공국 면허증이지
바로 이렇게 생겼지
기사에 넣게 이걸
복사해도 될까요?
프랭크 그건 가져도 된다
3 년전에 유효기간이 지났다
아...고마워요
뱃지는 어때요?
여분의 걸 빌릴 수 있나요?
아니, 그건 도와줄 수 없다
이건 폴라로이드에
특별주문한거야
아무도 이걸 얻을 순 없다
팬암 항공의 진짜 조종사가
되기 전에는...
팬암입니다
무엇을 도와 드릴까요?
유니폼 때문에 전화 드렸습니다
구매과로 거세요
고마워요
구매과입니다
샌프란시스코에 근무하는
부조종사입니다
어제밤에 뉴욕으로 날아왔습니다
문제는 3시간 후에
파리로 가야 합니다
어떻게 도와 드릴까요?
호텔에 유니폼을
세탁하라고 맡겼는데
잃어버린 것 같습니다
그들은 언제나 유니폼을
잃어버리죠
브로드웨이 9번가에 있는
웰빌 유니폼으로 가세요
그들이 유니폼을 공급 합니다
로즈씨한테 당신이 간다고
말할게요
조종사가 되기엔
어려 보이는군요
전 부조종사입니다
왜 이렇게 긴장하죠?
근무 첫주에 유니폼을 잃어버리면
기분이 어떻겠어요
긴장을 풀어요
팬암은 유니폼이 많아요
164 달러입니다
좋아요. 수표를 써 드릴게요
미안합니다. 수표나 현금은
받지 않아요
사원번호를 적으시면
팬암에 청구할 겁니다
다음번 월급에서 나갈 거에요
더 좋군요
아빠에게
정직한 사람은
두려워할게 없다고
언제나 얘기 하셨었죠
그래서 두려워하지 않으려고
노력하고 있어요
도망쳐 버려서 죄송해요
하지만 걱정하지 마세요
이제 모두 돌려받을 거에요, 아빠
약속해요
모두 돌려받을 거에요
진짜 조종사에요?
물론이지, 꼬마 아가씨
이름이 뭐지?
셜린
셜린, 만나서 반갑다
저도 만나서 반가워요
50, 70, 80, 90
100달러에요
파리에서 즐거운 시간 보내세요
언제나 그럽니다
실례합니다
존 모디카입니다
여기 지점장인데
방문해 주셔서 기쁩니다
만나서 반가워요, 존
- 다시 들르겠어요
- 좋아요
여기 전에 머문 적 있나요?
아뇨. 주로 서부 해안에
있었어요
방값으로 수표를
써 드려도 되나요?
- 문제없습니다
- 좋아요
개인수표로 써도 되나요?
항공사 직원 분은 100달러까지
현금으로 바꿔드립니다
월급수표는 300달러까지입니다
월급수표는 300달러라고 했나요?
아빠에게
팬암 항공의 조종사가
되기로 했어요
하늘에서 가장 믿음직한 이름...
저를 훈련 프로그램에
받아 들였어요
열심히 한다면
곧 날 수 있을 거라고 했어요
10 학년의 조앤나한테 연락해서
무도회에 못 데려가서
미안하다고 전해주세요
사랑하는 아들 프랭크가
- 안녕하세요?
- 좋아요, 고마워요
월급수표를 현금으로
바꾸고 싶어요
잠깐만요
실례합니다
많이 들으셨겠지만
이렇게 아름다운
눈은 처음 보았어요
언제나 듣는 소리죠
어떻게 해 드릴까요?
오...정말 미안합니다
지금은 현금이 없어요
은행은 한시간 안에 열겁니다
하지만 공항에서는
현금으로 바꿔 줄 겁니다
공항에서?
누가 공항에서 현금을
바꿔줘요?
항공사들 이죠
언제나 자기 직원들을 책임지죠
안녕하세요?
무임탑승이시죠?
뭐라고요?
마이애미로 무임탑승
해 드려요?
네
난 무임탑승하려고 해요
약간 늦었지만
접는 좌석은 있어요
이런걸 해본지 오래 되어서...
어떤게 접는 좌석이죠?
비행 잘 하세요
무임탑승하신 분인가요?
프랭크
올리버 기장님,
부조종사인 존 마크
기관사인 프레드 텔리에요
팬암의 프랭크 테일러입니다
태워주셔서 고맙습니다
좌석에 앉아요, 프랭크
이륙할 겁니다
어떤 기종을 타나요?
DC-8?
술 먹어서 못 탔나요?
다음 몇 달동안 비행 감각을
유지하기 위해
무임탑승을 하려고 해요
부끄러워하지 말아요
우리도 모두 그랬어요
- 앉으세요
- 고마워요
이륙한 다음에 마실 것
드릴까요?
우유
- 80 노트
- 확인
V1 회전
V2
상승
바퀴 올려
아빠에게
오늘은 졸업식이에요
전 이제 부조종사에요
한달에 1400달러와
복지혜택이 있어요
제일 좋은 점은
가족들은 공짜래요
그러니 엄마한테 새 수영복을 사서
짐 싸라고 얘기해 주세요
왜냐하면 크리스마스에 온 가족을
하와이로 데려갈 거에요
사랑해요 아빠
알로하, 프랭크
안녕, 무임탑승자씨
공짜 여행은 즐겁나요?
마시
이걸 떨어트렸나요?
당신 목에서
흘러내린 것 같군요
아니에요
아니에요...
그래요
왜 멈췄어요?
당신한테 할 말이 있어, 마시
여태까지 중에
제일 좋은 데이트 였어
마이애미 상호은행에 오신 걸
환영 합니다
어떻게 도와드릴까요?
제 이름은 프랭크 테일러이고
팬암의 부조종사입니다
여기서 수표를 바꾸고
당신과 함께 스테이크를
저녁으로 먹고 싶어요
그리고 수표를 확인하는
MICR 에 넣어요
수표 밑에
특별한 코드가 있어요
그 숫자들은 어디 있죠?
그것들은 바로 여기에...
- 바로 거기?
- 봤죠?
경로숫자라고 불러요
그럼 어디로
수표가 전해지죠?
나도 정확하게 몰라요
아무도 물어본 적 없어요
다음 경매는 폐업한
뉴저지 중앙은행에서 나온
MICR 입니다
이건 은행 수표에 사용되던
해독하고 코드화하는
기계입니다
누가 경매하겠어요?
미확인 범인이 동부해안에서
나타났습니다
지난 몇 주 동안
제가 표류라고 부르는 새로운
수표 위조법을 개발 했습니다
여러 은행에서 예금구좌를
만든 다음에
수표 밑의 경로숫자를
바꾸는 겁니다
다음 슬라이드
다음 슬라이드 부탁 합니다
리모콘이 고장 났어요
수동으로 해야 돼요
FBI 본부
워싱턴 DC
먼로 요원 옆에 있는
네모 버튼을 눌러요
틀이 끼었나 봐요
됐군요
고마워요
매뉴얼을 읽어 봐야겠군
미국연방 안에 있는
12개의 은행 지도입니다
슬라이드
모든 은행의 기계가 수표 밑의
이 숫자들을 읽습니다
슬라이드
그리고 알맞은 지점으로
그걸 보냅니다
칼, 이 은행관련 일들은
우리한테 생소하네
도대체 무슨 얘기를
하는 건지 말해 주겠나?
여기 동부해안 지점들의
숫자는 01, 06 이고
중부 지점들은
07, 08 이런 식입니다
수표 밑에 있는 숫자들이
뭔가를 뜻한다는 말인가?
이 모든 것들은 제가 이틀 전에
보고 드린 리포트에 있습니다
만약 당신이
02를 12로 바꾼다면
뉴욕에서 바꾼 그 수표는
뉴욕 지점으로 가지 않고
샌프란시스코 지점까지
돌아가야 됩니다
은행이 수표가 잘못됐다는 걸
아는데 2주가 걸립니다
그 수표가 전국을 도는 동안
범인이 한 장소에 머물면서
계속해서 쓸 수 있다는
뜻입니다
자네 내 아내하고
얘기하고 싶을거네
그녀가 내 수표책의
수지를 맞추니까...
다음 슬라이드...
아빠
내 아들이 파일럿이라니...
유니폼 멋지구나, 프랭크
어떻게 생각하세요?
앉으세요
아빠
엽서 받으셨어요?
물론이지
이 포크는 차갑구나
아니에요. 그건 차가운
샐러드 포크에요
여긴 고급 레스토랑이에요
아...여기 있어요
드릴 걸 가져 왔어요
그게 뭔데?
열어보세요
이거 괜찮은 거에요
1965 년형 캐딜락
뉴빌 컨버터블 열쇠에요
새거에요, 아빠
빨간색이고 내부는 흰색이에요
나눠진 좌석, 에어컨도 있어요
나한테 캐딜락을 주는 거니?
캐딜락 드리는 거에요
저기 아래층에 세워 두었어요
점심식사 다 하시면
엄마 집으로 몰고 가서
차에 태워 드라이브라도 할까요?
내가 새 차를 몰고 다니는걸
국세청에서 알면
무슨 일이 일어날지 아니?
난 여기까지
기차로 왔다. 프랭크
기차타고 집에 갈 거다
좋아요
전 돈이 아주 많아요
더이상 아무것도
필요 없을 거에요
날 걱정 하는거니?
아뇨. 걱정 하는건 아니에요
내가 차도 못 살 것 같니?
생쥐 두마리가 크림 바구니에
빠졌다. 프랭크
내가 둘 중에 어떤 거지?
그래요. 두 번째 생쥐죠
오늘 가게 옆으로 지나갔어요
가게를 당분간
닫아두어야 한다
이건 타이밍의 문제야. 프랭크
빌어먹을 정부가
내가 돈을 버는걸 알게 되었어
그대로 뺏길 순 없어서
그들을 속이려고
가게 문을 닫을 수밖에 없었다
조만간...
날 잊지 마라
이해해요
엄마하고 얘기하세요?
엄마는 고집쟁이다
네 엄마는...
걱정하지마라
싸우지 않고 엄마를
보낼 수는 없었다
우리를 위한 싸움...
아빠
우리가 만난 날 이후로...
아빠, 그 모든 남자들 중에서
아빠가 엄마를 집으로
데려다 줬어요
기억하세요?
2 개의 소대가
그 작은 홀에 앉아서
그녀가 춤추는 걸 봤지
그 마을 이름이 뭐라고?
몽트리샤드
난 불어를 한마디도 못했다
6 주후에 그녀는...
아내가 되었죠
내 아들이 오늘 캐딜락을
사 줬어요
건배를 안 할 수가 없군요
하늘에서 최고의 조종사를
위하여
아빠가 생각하는 것과는
달라요
전 그냥 부조종사에요
우리를 쳐다보는
사람들 보이니?
뉴욕에서 제일
영향력 있는 사람들이다
그들이 어깨너머로
훔쳐보면서
네가 오늘밤 어디로 갈지
궁금해 한다
어디로 갈거니, 프랭크?
아무도 절 쳐다보지 않아요
이국적인 곳이니?
그냥 어디로 가는지
말해다오
로스앤젤레스, 헐리우드
헐리우드?
나머지 사람들은
정말 바보들이다
난 빨간 드레스에
하이힐을 신고
브라자는 이렇게 튀어나와서
공원으로  두 푸에르토리코
놈들을 쫓아갔지
캘리포니아, 헐리우드
은행 강도범 가방이 떨어졌어
난 'FBI다. 꼼짝마'라고
소리쳤어
총을 꺼내려고 했는데
너무 커서  브라자 안에서
찾을 수가 없었어
그래서 꼭지를 쏴 버릴 뻔 했어
이건 아주 웃긴 얘기야
모두다 이 얘기에 웃지
질문할 게 있어요
헨데르스키씨?
위장 근무 하는게 그렇게 재밌는데
왜 은행일로 옮겼죠?
옮긴게 아니에요
위에서 다시 조정 했어요
근신 같은 거에요
근신중이에요
현장에서 일을 망쳤어요
폭스씨 당신은 어때요?
당신도 현장에서 망쳐서
근신 중인가요?
현장에서 일해 본 적이 없어요
법무부 사무실에서
배경조사만 했어요
어 그거 멋지군
팀을 만들어 달라고 했더니
최악이군
뭐 좀 물어봐도 될 까요
핸래티씨?
언제나 그렇게 심각한가요?
신경 쓰이나요, 헨더스씨?
그래요
신경 쓰이는군요
당신도 신경 쓰이나요, 폭스씨?
약간 그런것 같네요
내가 농담 하는걸
듣고 싶은가요?
그래요
농담을 듣고 싶군요
똑 똑
누구죠?
엿이나 먹어
그가 수표를 세장 바꿨어요
모두 깨끗했죠
오늘 이걸 예금하려고 했어요
문제 일으키고 싶지 않소
문제 없소
전혀 문제 없네요
그냥 이걸 가져 갈게요
고마워요
좋아요
왜냐하면 내 손님이
체포되는 건 싫거든요
무슨 말이에요?
그가 아직 여기 있어요?
201 호
고맙소
- 모퉁이에요
- 고맙다
- 계단
- 계단이라
머피씨 안녕하세요?
프랭크인가?
네, 프랭크에요
프랭크 잘 지내?
무릎은 어떠세요?
지금 병원에 가는 중이야
- 조심하세요
- 알았네, 프랭크
난 사무실로 돌아가겠어
전문가를 부르자고
이건 서류 위조범 이야
난 총도 없어
전 당신하고 가겠어요, 칼
그냥 눈이나 크게 뜨고
수상한 사람이 있나 살펴봐요
괜찮습니다, 부인
FBI 에요
201 호...
FBI
FBI 다
화장실 안에서 나와요
화장실 밖으로
손 올려
IBM 셀렉트릭 타자기를
썼군요
- 손 머리에 올려
- 5 초면 지문을 뜰 수 있어요
- 닥쳐
- 키보드 위에서
손 머리 위로 올려
- 여기 200장도 넘는 수표가 있어요
- 머리 위로 손 올려
수표들...
심지어 월급봉투도 있군요
내려 놔
- 떨어뜨려
- 진정해요
당신이 늦었어요. 알았어요?
내 이름은 알렌, 배리 알렌이에요
미국 정보부 소속 이죠
그 애는 창문으로
뛰어 내리려고 해서
내 동료가 잡고 있어요
무슨 말을 하는지 모르겠군
FBI 만 이 자식을
아는 줄 알았어요?
이봐요
정부 수표를 위조 했어요
종이를 조작해서...
도장도 찍어서
그 총 좀 내 얼굴에서
치워줄래요?
제발 부탁이에요
신경 쓰이게 만드는 군요
신분증을 보여줘요
물론이죠
제 지갑을 통째로 드리죠
제 총도 드릴까요?
이리 와서 총을 가져 가세요
이봐요, 이걸 봐요
밖에 좀 봐 주세요
창문 밖을 보세요
동료가 차 있는 곳으로
가고 있어요
내가 문을 열면 나쁜 놈들은
모두 오줌을 싸죠
창문 밖으로 뛰어내려서
내 차로 향했어요
이봐, 머피
LA 경찰에 다시 얘기해
아무도 내 현장에 들어오게
하고 싶지 않군
정보부에서 올 줄은
몰랐어요
걱정하지 말아요
이름이 뭐죠?
핸래티
칼 핸래티
- 신분증 좀 볼 수 있을까요?
- 여기
요즘은 조심해서
나쁠 것 없죠
운이 나쁘군요, 칼
5 분만 일찍 왔다면
당신이 잡았을텐데...
괜찮아요
10 초만 늦었다면
당신은 총 맞았어요
아래층에 내려가도 될까요?
이 자식 좀 보고 싶군요
물론이죠. 하지만
잠시만 앉아 있을래요
증거들 좀 아래에 갖다 둘게요
종업원이 들어와서
방을 정리할까봐 걱정 되네요
LA 경찰이 곧 올 겁니다
기다려요
당신 지갑은...
가지고 있어요
당신을 믿어요
정보부라고...
이봐
이런 젠장
어리석군요
바보 같은 실수를 했어요
잊어버리게
미확인 범인이
수백 명도 더 있네
이 자식은 확실히 잡을 수
있습니다
이 위조범이 한 가장
큰 실수는
내가 그의 얼굴을
본 겁니다
보고서를 읽어 보았네
180 센티미터, 갈색 머리에
27 에서 30살 정도 나이
72 킬로그램
그런 사람은 너무나 많네
난 그의 목소리를 들었어요, 존
얼굴도 봤다구요
이제 더 이상
숨을 수 없습니다
조심하게
넌 12년 동안 일했어
아무도 자네가
1층으로 내려가서
은행 위조범에 대해
책을 써도 신경쓰지 않네
그런 일이 언젠가 자네를
부서 책임자로 만들어 줄 거네
단지 이런 처지에
자네를 밀어 넣지 말게
어떤 처지 말입니까?
창피한 처지 말이야
존, 농담하나 해드릴까요?
그래, 물론이네
똑 똑...
제 다음 질문은
조종사가 은퇴하면
팬암이 매달 수표를 보내나요?
그렇네. 그건
복지혜택에 포함되네
그 수표는 얼마나 되죠?
얘야, 지금은 별로
얘기하고 싶지 않아
이 스카이맨이
날 미치게 만드는군
누가 스카이맨 이죠?
전국을 돌아다니면서
팬암 조종사라고 하는 놈이지
신문 칼럼에
그 놈에 대한게 나왔네
계속 말하지만
그 놈은 내 문제가 아냐
이 자식은 팬암 조종사가 아냐
아마 다른 항공사일 거야
유나이티드나 TWA
콘메도, 이스턴...
스카이맨 이라고
신문들은 이 자식을 좋아하네
하늘의 제임스 본드라고 부르지
뭐라구요?
본드
제임스 본드
말해줘, 질.
왜 그가 그랬지?
- 수영하기를 좋아하나 봐요
- 이봐, 이봐
12 분후면 착륙 합니다
가볍게 할까요?
아니면 거칠게?
진정되지 않는군요
고맙군요
총보다는 하는게 더 좋아요
안녕 아가씨
이게 바로 그 양복인가요?
맞아요
이게 영화에 나온
바로 그 양복이에요
좋아요. 세벌 주세요
알겠습니다, 플레밍씨
이제 필요하신 건 타고 다닐
조그만 외제 경주용차군요
- 안녕?
- 안녕
전에 본 적이 있나요?
아마도...
몇 년 전에 세븐틴 이란
잡지 표지모델이었어요
그래요
그 모델이군요, 그렇죠?
쉐릴
락커에 당신 사진을
붙이곤 했죠
밖에 세워져 있는 게
당신 차들 중 하나인가요?
그래요. 그중의 하나죠
싸인 얻을 수 있을까요?
방에 펜이 있나요?
당신 같은 남자는 원하는 건
뭐든지 살 수 있죠
호텔 상점에서 산 카드군요
카드 마술이 보고 싶은가요?
이 카드 얼마죠?
55 센트 일겁니다
아래층 호텔 선물가게에서
날 판다면
당신은 얼마를 낼 수 있죠?
미안해요...
뭘 얼마에 산다고요?
하룻밤 전부
하룻밤을 보낸다면
얼마 주실 거죠?
쉐릴, 정말 모르겠어요
겁먹지 말아요
제안을 해봐요
300 달러?
꿈도 꾸지 마요
500 달러?
600 달러
꿈도 꾸지 마요
1000 달러
좋아요
바로 돌아올게요
기다려봐요
어디로 가세요
현금으로 바꿀려고
아래층으로 내려가요
새벽 3시에 이 호텔에서
1000 달러를 바꿔줄 것 같아요?
뉴욕저축은행 수표에요
금처럼 현금으로 바꿀 수 있죠
그들이 의심할 거라고
생각 안 하나요?
볼 수 있을까요?
은행 수표군요
저한테 이서하세요
안돼요. 그럴 수는 없어요
이건 1400 달러짜리 수표에요
우린 1000 달러에 합의 했잖아요
제가 당신한테 400 달러를 준다면
나한테 그 수표를 주겠어요?
좋은 방법 이군요
이거 누구 거죠?
핸래티 입니다
메리 크리스마스
안녕, 칼
안녕
배리 알렌
정보부
지난 몇 시간동안
당신을 찾았어요
뭘 원하는 거야?
지난번 일을
사과하고 싶어요
아냐. 사과할 필요 없어
언제나 크리스마스이브에
일하나요, 칼?
내가 자원 했네
집에 일찍 가야
가족도 없어
결혼반지를 껴서
가족이 있는 줄 알았어요
아니, 가족이 없어
나하고 얘기하고 싶나?
만나서 얘기하자
좋아요
다이버슨암스의 스위트룸
3113호에 있어요
아침에는 주말 보내러
라스베가스로 가요
다시 날 놀릴 수
있을 것 같나
넌 베가스로 가지 않아
다이버슨암스에
있는 것도 아니고
크리스마스이브에
20명의 요원을
네가 말한 호텔에
보내게 하고 싶나?
문을 두드리는 순간
우리는 바보가 되는 거지
당신을 속여서 정말 미안해요
- 정말 그래요
- 아냐
정말 사과하고 싶어요
나한테 미안해 할 필요 없어
진실은...
너 인줄 알았어
수갑을 채우진 않았지만
난 알았어
당신이 알고 있는 걸
사람들한테 말해요
그럼 이걸 말해줘
비밀요원 배리 알렌
내가 지갑을 안 열어볼 줄
어떻게 알았지?
양키스가 언제나 이기는
이유하고 같아요
아무도 줄무늬에서
눈을 뗄 수가 없어요
양키스가 이기는 건
미키 맨틀이 있어서야
유니폼 때문이 아니라고
확신해요, 칼?
내가 확신하는걸 알려주지
넌 잡힐 거야
어떤 방법이든...
이건 수학적인 사실이야
라스베가스식이지
주인이 언제나 이겨
칼, 미안하지만 가야 겠어요
단지 사과하려고
전화한 건 아니지?
뭐에요?
넌 전화할 데가 없는 거야
커피 더 드릴까요?
수집가세요?
뭐에?
만화책의 대장들
빅 프리즈나 금빛거인 같은...
무슨 말을 하는 거야?
배리 알렌
더 플래시
얘야
만화책 말하는 거야?
네. 만화책이요
플래시에 배리 알렌이 나와요
고마워
그는 만화책을 읽어
만화책이라고
배리 알렌이 플래시야
칼, 천천히 말해요
무슨 말을 하는지 모르겠어요
그는 아이야
모든게 들어맞아
그래서 지문을 찾을 수 없었어
그래서 기록도 없었고
뉴욕경찰에 연락해서
뉴욕시에서 가출한
모든 청소년을 찾아봐
공항도 잊지 말고
그는 온 나라에 수표를 뿌렸어
왜 뉴욕이죠?
양키스 때문이야
양키스에 대한 걸 말했어
목록에 어디쯤 왔나?
53 번 아백날리
좋은 아침입니다. 부인
전화 드린 FBI 요원입니다
기다리고 있었어요
모두 배고프신가요?
사라리 케익을 준비 했어요
제 남편 잭은 변호사에요
당신 첫 남편은 어떤가요?
아백날리 부인
아백내일이에요
하지만, 반즈 부인이라고
불리는 걸 더 좋아해요
프랭크 윌리엄 아백내일
그가 군대에 있었다고 나오는군요
전쟁 중에 만나셨나요?
네. 전 프랑스의
아주 작은 마을에 살았죠
몽트리샤드
사라리에 대해선
좀처럼 듣기 힘든 곳 이죠
좀 드세요
사라리 싫어하는 사람은 없죠
당신이 실종 신고를 했죠
프랭크 윌리엄 주니어라는
가출한 소년을...
프랭키는 괜찮은가요?
체이스맨하탄 은행의 닫힌 계좌의
수표를 쓴 걸 알고 계셨나요?
네. 경찰은 그가
범죄자라고 생각 했죠
그가 한 짓은 중죄에요
그건 천 달러도 안 되는 돈이에요
그 애 나이가 몇인지 아세요?
많은 경찰들을 불러들이고
내 아들이 조그만 실수를 했다고
절 두렵게 만드는 군요
그앤 열일곱살 이에요
애들은 모두 먹고
잠잘 곳이 필요해요
저희도 이해합니다, 부인
아들 사진 가지고 계세요?
네 그래요
졸업앨범이 있어요
좋았어...
모든 사무소에 사진을 보내게
이름은 프랭크 아백내일 주니어이고
17살이야
프랭키는 괜찮은 건가요?
무슨 잘못을 했나요?
부인, 아드님은
수표 위조를 했습니다
수표 위조?
잠깐만요. 제가 대신 갚을께요
요즘 교회 일을 도와주고 있어요
그애가 갚아야 될 돈이 얼마죠?
지금까지 130만 달러입니다
리버벤드 아파트
애틀란타, 조지아
- 안녕, 멜라니. 잘 지내?
- 좋아
집안에선 금연이야. 부탁이야
여기 너무 좋다
그래? 이거 받아
기꺼이 그럴게
제임스, 제임스
제발 오디오에서
좀 떨어져 있어
알아들었어?
이건 예민한 거야
그런 식으로 다루지 마
젠장..
테리, 이건 이태리제야
앞을 잘 보라구
그냥 셔츠야, 친구
프랭크, 빨리 와봐
랜스가 거실바닥으로
떨어 졌어요
실례합니다.
랜스 애클범이 어디 있죠?
고마워요
그렇게 서있지 말고 다시는
그러지 않겠다고 말해요
난 일하러
다시 돌아가야겠어
닥터 블래어, 닥터 블래어
이봐
괜찮아요?
그가 돌기를 제거하라고 해서
그렇게 했어요
하지만 금속판도
제거하라고는 안했어요
이봐요, 괜찮아요
그만 울어요
이름이 뭐죠?
브렌다
브렌다...
난 당신 걱정을 하지는
않아요
의사들이 모든걸
아는건 아니에요
근무 첫째 주에요
날 해고할 거에요
아니, 아니에요
아무도 해고하지 않아요
일을 잘할 거라고 믿어요
안 그래요
확실해요
내 친구 랜스 애클범의 상태에
대해 묻는다면
잠깐 알아봐 주겠어요?
대기중인 간호사는
회복실로...
애클범씨는 발목을 삐었어요
애쉴랜드 선생님이
7호 진찰실에서 치료해요
봤어요?
아무 문제 없어요
이게 응급 차트에요
저기 파란 별 보이나요?
그건 그 환자는
검사 받았다는 뜻이에요
치료를 받은 다음에는
여기에 빨간 원을 그려요
알았죠?
교정기 마음에 드는군요
괜찮은 것 같아요
난 작년에 떼었어요
난 싫어했죠
최악이었죠
마우스피스처럼 보였어요
정말 좋은 치아를 가졌군요
고마워요
당신은 미소가 예쁘네요
아니 정말이에요
그 교정기가 정말
잘 어울려요
고마워요
천만에요
-브렌다
-네?
병원에서 사람을 뽑나요?
잘 모르겠어요
뭘 하고 싶은데요?
난 의사예요
아빠에게
잠깐 다른 일을 하려고 해요
밤에 병원에서 일하려고 해요
정말 좋은 사람들이에요
지면에 발을 대고
있으니까 좋아요
매일밤 같은 침대에서 일어나요
프랭크 코너스
같이 살 사람을 만날지
누가 알겠어요
하버드 의대?
학급에서 일등?
남캘리포니아 어린이 병원
정말 인상적인 이력서군요
코너스 선생
불행하게도 지금 필요한 일은
자정부터 8시까지
응급실 관리자가 필요해요
6명의 인턴과 20명의 간호사를
관리해야 돼요
하지만...
당신은 전혀 관심 없겠군요
전에는 항상 제 간호사는
제가 골랐어요
코널리 선생
-해리스 선생
-여기 있습니다
-애쉴랜드 선생
-코너스 선생님
매일밤 할건가요?
그럴겁니다, 애쉴랜드 선생
만약 늦는다면
쪽지를 가져오세요
베스포드양
메이스양
-스트롱양
-네
브라운 간호사
샌포드 간호사?
우리한테 오기전에
대동맥이 드러났군
분당 60방울쯤 떨어지니
다시 계산해 보게
화상의 정도가
어떻다고 생각하나?
살가죽의 20% 정도가
2도에서 3도 화상을 입었어요
-동의하나요?
-동의합니다
소아과로 보냅시다
의학박사 프랭크 코너스
호프 간호사 의국으로
-안녕, 브렌다
-안녕, 코너스 선생님
-서명해 주셔야 돼요
-고마워요
저한테 다른 점 발견
못 하셨나요?
-교정기를 떼었군요
-그래요
밤새도록
얘기하려고 했어요
아주 잘 됐군요
떼어낼 때 아팠나요?
아주 이상하죠?
계속 혀로 만져보게 돼요
아주 미끄러워요
느낌이 좋죠, 그렇죠?
네, 아주 좋아요
오 세상에...
미안해요
코너스 선생님 응급실로
가야 되나요?
아니, 아냐
응급실에는
당직의사가 있어
괜찮을거야
만약 그가 수술중이라면?
내가 가야 된다고
생각해요?
어서오세요, 코너스 선생님
이보게
뭐가 문제인 것 같나?
자전거 사고에요
경골이 골절이고
5인치쯤 찢어졌네요
해리스 선생, 동의 하나?
뭐에 동의 하죠?
애쉴랜드 선생이
방금 얘기한 것...
동의 하나?
음...이건 자전거 사고에요
이 애가 우리한테 말했어요
-동의해?
-동의?
엑스레이를 찍고
뼈를 맞춰서
걸을 수 있는 기브스를
해야겠어요
아주 좋아요, 애쉴랜드 선생
아주 좋아요
내가 필요하지
않은 것 같군요
계속하세요
진짜로?
그랬나?
뭘 동의한거지?
청소부 창고
내 집에서 뭐하는 거요?
프랭크 아백내일 시니어죠?
당신 경찰이 아니군요
FBI 특수요원 핸래티입니다
경찰이 아니에요
집주인이 당신이 경찰이
아니라고 했어요
날 체포할 작정이라면
다른 양복을 입고 싶군요
-괜찮죠?
-당신을 체포하러 온게 아니에요
아들을 찾으러 왔어요
곤란한 처지죠
어디 있는 줄 아나요?
그가 어디 있는지 말한다면
엄마한테 얘기하지 않는다고
약속할 수 있나요?
물론이죠
프랭크는 가짜 신분증을
만들어서
해병대에 지원해서
베트남에 갔어요
그 아이는 지구 반대편에
있어요
빌어먹을 정글을
기어다니고
공산주의자와 싸우고 있죠
그러니 제발 내 집으로
오지 마세요
내 아이를 범죄자라고 부르지 말아요
왜냐하면 그 아이는...
범죄자라고 말하지 않았어요
아백내일씨
그가 곤란하다고 말했죠
만약 전화해서
대화하고 싶다면
전화번호 여기 있어요
아빠에게...
리버벤드 아파트...
당신은 아빠가 아니죠?
뭐라고 하셨죠?
만약 당신이 아버지라면...
아냐. 난 아들을
포기하지 않겠어
아들을 포기하지 않겠어
네. 이해합니다
숀, 숀
받아 적어
리버벤드 아파트
415 랜도버
애틀랜타, 조지아
공항으로 가고 있는 중이네
4시간후에 팀을 만나겠어
바이 바이
이봐, 괜찮아
-울 필요 없어
-미안해요
프랭크 정말 미안해요
브렌다 내 말 들어 봐
당신이 처녀이건 상관 안 해
정말이야
기다릴 수 있어
난 처녀가 아니에요
2년 전에 유산했어요
제 부모님 친구분이
해줬어요
나하고 아버지가
거기로 갔어요
내가 퇴원할때쯤
집에서 내쫓았어요
내가 유산을 해서
더 이상 딸이 아니래요
이봐...
정말 미안해요
제발 나한테 화내지 말아요
제발...
나한테 화내지 말아요
아니야, 아냐
이제 내가 당신 부모님한테
얘기해보면 어때?
아마 내가 일을
해결할 수 있을거야
엄마는 항상 집으로
돌아오라고 하세요
아빠는 변호사예요
브렌다
만약 당신이 의사와
약혼을 한다면?
뭐가 바뀌지 않을까?
뭐라고?
내가 만약 당신 부모한테
간다면
그리고 당신 아버지한테
말할거야
당신과 결혼을
허락해 달라고...
비었어요
아무도 없어요
하버드 대학교
프랭크 코너스
뉴올리언스
코너스 선생
루터교 신자인가요?
네. 루터교입니다
그냥 프랭크라고
불러주세요
프랭크, 자네가
기도를 할텐가?
불편하지 않다면...
물론이죠
작은 생쥐 두마리가
크림 바구니에 빠졌습니다
첫번째 생쥐는 재빨리 포기하고
익사했습니다
하지만 두번째 생쥐는
아주 분투하여
결국, 크림을 버터로
만들었습니다
그리고 걸어 나왔습니다
아멘
정말 아름다운 얘기군요
생쥐가 크림을
버터로 바꾸었다...
맞아요
고마워요
프랭크, 뉴올리언스에서는
어느 병원에서 일할지 결정했나요?
솔직히 얘기드린다면
다시 법률일 하는 걸
생각하고 있어요
오 세상에...
당신 의사인가
아니면 변호사인가?
의대에 가기 전에
캘리포니아에서
변호사 시험에 통과했어요
1년동안 연수를 받다가
소아과의사가 되면 어떨까
생각했어요
당신은 놀라움으로
가득찼군요
그래요
오 세상에...
의사에다가 변호사라니...
브렌다가 대박을
터뜨린것 같네요
어느 법대를 나왔죠?
버클리요
세상에, 버클리래요
아빠도 거기 다니셨죠?
프랭크가 당신 밑에서
일해도 되겠네요, 로저
좋은 검사보를 찾기 힘들다고
했었잖아요
그래도 돼요, 아빠?
제발 아빠하고
일하게 해주세요
자네가 버클리 다닐때도
스네이크 홀랜스워스가 가르치고 있었나?
홀랜스워스...
네. 심술쟁이 영감
홀랜스워스, 맞죠?
더 야비해졌어요
그리고 그 개도
여전히 있나?
그의 조그만 강아지 이름이
뭔지 말해주겠나?
죄송합니다
그 개는 죽었어요
불행한 일이군
네
의사면서 변호사이고
루터교라 이거지
그래 자네 정체가 뭔가?
프랭크
왜냐하면 자네가 내 딸한테
결혼하자고 할 것 같아서야
난 알 권리가 있네
뭘 알고 싶으신거죠?
진실이네
진실을 말해주게, 프랭크
여기서 뭐하는건가?
자네같은 친구가
브렌다와 뭐하는 건가
내 축복을 원한다면
내 딸을 원한다면
자네한테 지금 듣고 싶네
진실은...
전 의사도 아니고
변호사도 아니고
비행기 조종사도 아니고
사실 아무것도 아니에요
따님과 사랑에 빠진
아이일 뿐이에요
아냐
자네가 뭔지 아나?
자넨 로맨틱하네
우리같은 남자는
여자가 없으면 안되지
나도 고백해야겠네
나도 똑같이
바보같은 짓을 했었지
5일만에 캐럴한테
청혼을 했네
주머니엔 25센트
두개밖에 없었고
신발에는 구멍이 나 있었지
왜냐하면 그녀가 천생연분인걸
알았기 때문이네
결혼하게, 프랭크
겁먹지 말고...
나한테 물어보러 온 질문을
이제 하게
선생님...
뉴올리언스에서 변호사 시험보려면
어떻게 해야 되죠?
다른 질문말이야
저 문으로 가세요
루이지애나주 변호사 시험
행운을 빌어요, 코너스씨
고마워요
1969년 12월 26일
이봐, 프랭크
난 도대체 모르겠네
어떻게 루이지애나주
변호사 시험을 통과했나?
뭐가 달라지죠?
누군가 대신 시험을 봐줬나?
칼, 전 오랫동안 감옥에
있을거에요
정말로 뭐가 달라지죠?
간단한 질문인데...
그거 먹을건가요?
그래
나중에 먹으려고 하네
저한테 나눠줄래요?
아니
저한테 그거 주면
말해줄께요
곧 알아낼거야
여기서 필립 릭비와
법인법 관련 일을 할거네
이제 자리 잡고
책상도 정리하게
고맙습니다
우린 12시 30분에
점심을 먹을거네
법무장관하고
맥킬 주지사하고 함께 말야
바로 그와...
주지사라고요?
철자가 맞았나?
물론입니다
프랭크 코너스
검사보
축하하네
-고맙습니다
-환영하네
이제...
이 사진을 보십시요
스튜어트씨
그가 죽은걸 발견한 곳의
당신 친구 사진입니다
이건 그 사진의 부분을
확대한 겁니다
이건 취소된 수표에 있는
피고의 서명 사진입니다
이건 그 서명을
확대한 겁니다
그 서명은 루이지애나 주재산을
가로채는 일을 의논하고 있는
사이먼 부인에게 쓴 편지의
서명과 일치합니다
재판장님
배심원 여러분
이건 피고가 사실상
거짓말을 하고 있다고
의심할 수밖에 없는
증거입니다
코너스씨
이건 예심입니다
피고도 없고
배심원도 없습니다
나밖에는 없어요
이보게
도대체 뭐 잘못 먹었나
-미치 시작했니?
-로저
미치에요
조금 놓쳤군
오늘밤 싱얼롱의
스튜디오 방청객은
뉴욕시 샌모니카 교회의
어린이 합창단입니다
아일랜드인을 위한
노래 몇 곡 하시겠어요?
모두다..
여기 켈리 본 사람 있나요?
K~E~L~L~Y
미소를 본 적 있나요
머리는 빨간색이고
눈은 푸른색...
그는 완전히 아일랜드인이죠
여기 켈리 본 사람 있나요?
에머랄드섬으로부터
온 켈리를
여기 켈리 본 사람 있나요?
K~E~L~L~Y
미소를 본 적 있나요
머리는 빨간색이고
눈은 푸른색...
그는 완전히 아일랜드인이죠
여기 켈리 본 사람 있나요?
날 감싸안아요
달콤한 안을 수 있는 그대여
대신할 수 없는 그대여
단지 그대를 슬쩍 보아도
내 심장은 쿵쿵 뛰죠
당신...오직 당신만이
내 안의 집시를 꺼내죠
아빠
여기서 뭐하는 거지?
뵈러 왔어요
왜 이렇게 입고 있어요?
일자리를 잡았다
정부의 일이지
내가 뭘하고 있는지 아니?
좋은 변호사 아니?
이제 저도 변호사에요
이 편지를 봐라
국세청이 또 한번...
두가지 벌칙에 대한거다
그들이 케익을 먹고
이제 빵부스러기도 원하지
난 고소할거다
빠져나올 수가 없다
앉아라
날 감시하려고 해
협박을 하고...
그거 아니?
그거 알아?
남은 일생동안
날 쫓아오게 만들거다
다시 만나서 반가워요
아빠
앉으세요
보여드릴게 있어요
이걸 드리려고 왔어요
약혼파티 초대장이에요
아빠 저 결혼해요
제가 결혼한다는게
믿어지세요?
이제부터는 아무것도
걱정하지 마세요
새 캐딜락을 드리고
6만달러짜리 집도 살께요
모두 다 돌려 받을꺼에요
모든 보석들
모든 모피들, 모든걸
우리한테서 뺏어간 모든걸
돌려 받을꺼에요
이제...
엄마가 아빠 이렇게 입고
다니는거 아세요?
상자 몇가지를
가지러 왔었다
괜찮아요
왜 그런지 아세요?
우리하고 결혼식에
함께 갈꺼에요
새로운 양복을
사드릴께요, 아빠
맨하튼 이글표 3단 단추에
검은색 양복을...
멋져 보일꺼예요
그건 좋다만
그녀는 날 보지 않을거다
전화해 보셨어요?
지금 당장
걸어보시는게 어때요?
지금 당장 걸어보세요
아빠. 여기요
아빠. 그냥 저를 위해서
걸어주세요
전화 걸어서 엄마한테
일등석 2장 있다고 하세요
네 엄마는 지금은 내 친구
잭 반스하고 결혼했다
그들은 롱아일랜드에
집이 있다
FBI 요원이 날 찾아왔었다
넌 추적당하고 있어
미국 정부가 쫓아오고 있어
달까지 힘내라
아빠, 끝났어요
전 그만 둘거에요
하지만...넌...
그들은 널 잡지 못해, 프랭크
아빠, 엄마는 그러지 않았어요
-앉지 그러니?
-왜 아빠한테 그러겠어요
나하고 앉아서
뭐 한잔 마셔라
난 네 아빠야
그럼 그만두라고 하세요
그만두라고...
넌 멈출 수가 없어
어딜 가는거니?
이봐, 프랭크
어딜 가니?
오늘밤 어디로 가니?
오늘밤 이국적인데로
가는거니?
타히티, 하와이?
핸래티입니다
안녕, 칼
메리 크리스마스
코너스 선생
안녕하신가요?
칼, 전 몇달전부터
의사가 아니었어요
흠...난 크리스마스이브에
사무실에 앉아있네
뭘 원하나?
좋아요
끝내고 싶어요
결혼도 하고...
전 정착을 해요
넌 거의 5백만 달러를 훔쳤어
결혼때문에 전화걸었나?
선물?
그런식으로
빠져나갈순 없네, 프랭크
사실을 말하려고 걸었어요
사실이 아냐
넌 잡힐거고
감옥에 갈거야
어디로 갈 수 있을것 같나?
제발 나한테 집을 줘요, 칼
제발...
난 점점 가까이
가고 있어, 그렇지?
내가 점점 다가가서
넌 겁먹은 거야
난 널 알아
넌 캐럴을 만나서
새우를 먹고
찰스호숫가에 있는
호텔에 머물렀어
도망쳐봐
해 보라구...
수표가 네가 뭘하는지
다 말해주지
날 쫓는걸 멈춰요
난 멈출 수가 없어
이건 내 일이야
괜찮아요, 칼
그냥 한번 부탁한 거에요
이봐
메리 크리스마스
난 내 일을 사랑한다
좋아.
모든 신문을 가져와
지난 두달동안
루이지애나의 모든 신문을
뭘 찾는거죠?
약혼 발표야
-코너스라는 이름으로
-코너스라고?
이봐 칼. 지금쯤은
이름을 바꿨을거야
바꿀 수가 없어
그녀가 코너스라고
생각하고 있어
이름을 바꾸면
그녀을 잃게 돼
-축하하네
-즐거운 시간 보내세요
-안녕
-계속 춤 추세요
어디 가는거예요?
화장실에 잠깐 가는거야
알았어요
좋은 저녁입니다
전 FBI의 핸래티입니다
이 집 주인을 뵐 수 있을까요?
모시고 오겠습니다
바로 저깁니다
-아 로저 잘 지냈나?
-안녕 벤
좋은 저녁입니다, 신사분들
난 로저 스트롱이요
칼 핸래티, FBI
여기는 헨데르스키하고
폭스 요원입니다
파티를 방해해서
죄송합니다
천만에요
뭘 도와 드릴까요?
별일 아닙니다
신랑을 만나고 싶습니다
무슨 문제가 있나요?
자기 날 불렀어요?
이리 와요
사람들이 찾을거에요
우리 약혼식을
빠질 수는 없어요
뭘 하는 거에요?
뭐가 잘못 된거죠?
-우린 떠나야 돼요
-뭐라고요?
-브렌다, 날 사랑하지?
-그래요
내 말은 어떤 일이 있어도
날 사랑하냐구
그래요
내가 아프거나 가난하거나
심지어 다른 이름을 감췄어도
날 사랑해?
프랭크 어디서
그런 돈이 났어요?
브렌다, 들어봐
내 이름...
내 이름은 상관없어
내 이름은 프랭크 코너스야
그래서 자기하고 있는거지
하지만 우린 모두
비밀이 있어
때때로 난 여행을 할 때
프랭크 테일러라는 이름을 써
그게 내 비밀이야
-프랭크 테일러라고요?
-그래 프랭크 테일러. 알겠어?
프랭크 블랙
-프랭크 블랙?
-그건 상관없어
왜 이런 말들을
하는거에요?
브렌다...
더 이상 거짓말 하고 싶지 않아
알았어?
난 의사가 아냐
의대에 가 본적도 없어
난 변호사도
하버드 졸업생도
루터교도 아냐
브렌다 난 1년 반쯤 전에
16살 때 집에서 도망쳤어
프랭크
당신 루터교가 아니에요?
브렌다 이 돈들 보이지?
이 돈들 보이지?
더 있어. 아주 많이...
우리 여생을 위한
충분한 돈이 있어
봐
프랭크 장난치지 말아요
당신은 프랭크 코너스이고
28살이예요
왜 나한테 거짓말 했어요?
브렌다
당신 이름을 알고 싶어요
-내 말 들어봐
-이름을 말해요
원하는 곳은 어느곳에서나
살 수 있어
날 믿어야 돼, 브렌다
-날 믿어?
-응
날 사랑해, 브렌다?
-사랑하냐구
-사랑해요
실례합니다
이쪽은 핸래티씨이고
제 아내 캐럴입니다
-미스터?
-핸래티입니다, 부인
핸래티씨군요
프랭크하고 브렌다 못 봤어?
이층에 간 것 같아요
프랭크
브렌다 이리로 와
좋아. 이틀 후에 마이애미
국제공항에서 만나자
부모님이 잠든 후에
집을 빠져나와서
택시를 타고 와
택시 기사한테
이 돈을 주고
밤새도록 달리라고 해
브렌다 아침 10시에 만나
아침 10시...
알았어?
어느 방이죠?
저기 구석방이네
잘 들어
마이애미에 있는
국제공항이야
알았어? 말해봐
마이애미 국제공항
-무슨 일이 있어도
-택시를 잡아타고
-10시까지 오는 거야
-10시까지 갈 거야
무슨 일이 있어도
이틀 후에
이틀 후에, 브렌다
이틀 후에 무슨 일이 있어도
10시까지 갈께요
아무한테도 말하지 마
브렌다
지금 약속해 줘
알았어. 제발 가기전에
이름을 말해줘
말해줘
프랭크 윌리엄 아백내일 주니어
마이애미 국제 공항
택시
브렌다...
이 자식 나타나지 않았어
아주 똑똑하군
오늘이 아니면
내일이라도 나타날 거예요
이 나라를 떠나기 전에
잡아야 돼요
그는 여권도 없어요
지난 여섯달동안 그는
하버드하고 버클리 졸업생이었어
그는 여권을 얻을 수
있을거야
모든 요원들을 여기 마이애미
국제공항에 배치하게
전처럼 행동 요령대로...
마이애미 경찰에
요청했어요
25명씩 2교대로 50명의
제복경찰을 보내줬어요
우리 요원들이 100명도 넘게
한 공항에 있어요
좀 분산시켜야
하지 않을까요?
아니. 여기로 나갈거야
그가 차를 빌려서
뉴욕이나 애틀랜타에 있는
공항으로 안 갈지 어떻게 알죠?
왜냐하면 내가
뉴욕에 없기 때문이야
난 애틀랜타에
있는것도 아니지
네. 프랭크 로버트입니다
이 지역에 있는
모든 대학에서
팬암이 올해 새로운 직원채용
프로그램을 시작했어요
내일 아침에 캠퍼스에
들르도록 하죠
모두 와주셔서
고맙습니다
오늘이 끝날때쯤 8명의
젊은 숙녀들을 뽑겠습니다
팬암의 미래의 스튜어디스
프로그램의 일원으로...
이 8명의 아가씨들은
나와 함께 유럽으로 가서
두달동안 고객서비스에 대한
교육을 받을겁니다
팬암의 스튜어디스가 되려면
어떻게 해야 되는지
직접 알아내십시요
두 사람씩 명단을 만들게
두사람중 한명이 책임을 진다
알았나?
-헨데르스키
-네
제복입은 경찰들이
보도하고 입구를 지키고 있나?
이봐
남자 화장실을 정기적으로
확인하게
너 여기로
미래의 스튜어디스의
자격이 뭘까...
음 그건...전 친절하고
정말 잘 도와주고
승객들이 환영받는다는
느낌을 갖도록...
고도 3백피트에서
1시간에 6천마일을 여행하고
내 짐은 모두 꾸려졌고
난 떠날 준비가 되었네
아일린 앤더슨
메기 액커
데브라 조 맥밀란
캔디 헤스킨
마이애미 국제 공항
저기 앞에 있는 사람
금발 아냐?
조종사일 거야
그렇겠지
칼 핸래티씨 전화 받으세요
핸래티입니다
칼, 당신 무전기가
작동 안해요
입구에 팬암 유니폼을 입은 사람이
하얀색 포드에 앉아 있어요
미리 예단하지 말게
얼굴을 봤나?
이 자식 조종사 모자를 썼어요
칼, 이 놈인것 같아요
비켜, 비켜
프랭크 나와
프랭크?
차에서 나오게
손은 위로 올리고
쏘지 마세요
전 그냥 운전사에요
어떤 남자가 공항에서
100달러를 주면서
이 유니폼을 입고
기다리라고 했어요
누가 시킨거야?
이봐
핸래티
7개월후
남미, 호주
싱가폴, 이집트
그 녀석은 사라졌고
완전히 통제불능이에요
왜 나한테 연락이 안 왔지?
아무도 연락하지 않았어요
은행은 지난주까지 무슨 일이
일어났는지도 몰랐어요
그런 불가능해
이건 가짜가 아니라
그들은 잡을수가 없어요
뭔가 다른거에요
그가 뭘하는건가?
진짜 수표를 만들고 있어요
이건 너무 잘 만들어서 항공사들은
차이점을 모릅니다
마지막 수표가 일주일전에
마드리드에서 바꿔졌어요
제 추측엔
아직 거기 있는것 같습니다
우린 오늘 바로
출발해야 됩니다
-어디로?
-스페인
스페인으로 가고 싶다고?
사실 수표를 만든 곳으로
돌아가고 있어요
그래서 유럽으로 돌아간거죠
지도를 보세요
원을 그리고 있어요
수표가 떨어져가고 있어요
저도 알아요
이게 장거리 추적이라는걸
우린 마드리드로부터
추적할 수 있어요
우린 아직 그를
잡을 수 있어요
미안하네, 칼
그를 여기서 잡을 수 없다면
거기서 그를 잡을 수 없는거네
우린 그를 도망치게 할거에요
아니, 칼
자네가 그를 도망치게 한거네
완벽한 116번째 물건이군
색깔 분리가 완벽해요
전혀 번지지 않았어요
미국에는 이렇게 할 수 있는
사람이 없어요
우리 말고는 아무도 없죠
어디서 인쇄된 거죠?
어떤 괴물이 인쇄한 거네
괴물...
하이델버그와 아이스트라
하이델버그
거물이야
4가지 색이고
냄새를 맡아보게
잉크없이 투톤처리를 했어
이런걸 어디서 인쇄했을까요?
독일, 영국, 프랑스...
프랑스!
프랭크의 엄마가 프랑스에 있는
마을을 얘기했었어.
사라리가 없는 곳이야
프랭크의 아버지를 만난
마을 말이야
그래요.
전 기억 못 하겠어요...
그건 M으로 시작해
모...이런건데
폭스씨?
그래요, 그래
질문은 남편을 전쟁중에
만났나요?
답은 그래요...
사라리를 들어 본적도 없는
프랑스의 아주 작은
마을에서 만났어요
그 마을 이름을 적었는지
말해주게
몽트리샤드
1967년, 크리스마스 이브
프랑스, 몽트리샤드
칼? 칼!
메리 크리스마스
어떻게 우린 언제나 크리스마스에
얘기를 하게 되지?
매년 크리스마스때마다
당신하고 얘기를 해
쇼는 끝났어, 프랭크
넌 체포됐어
이봐, 배고픈가?
콩 좀 먹을래?
내가 프랑스에서
제일 좋은 콩을 사왔어
24명의 프랑스 경찰이
밖에서 기다리고 있네
-그들은 널 잡고 싶어 하네
-한 입 먹어 볼래요?
-미국인의 도움은 바라지 않지
-배고픈가요? 한 입 먹어볼래요?
내가 자네한테 수갑을 채우기
전에는 못 들어온다고 말했네
어..총이 있나요?
총 있어요?
-총 없나요?
-없어
총이 없군요
그리고 나한테 말하길...
지금 밖에
24명의 프랑스 경찰관이
당신을 도와주러
와 있다고 했나요?
그렇게 말했나요?
그래
좋아요, 좋아
여긴 창문이 없어요
정문으로 살짝 보겠어요
아냐, 아냐
내가 빨리 나가서
신호를 보내겠다고 했네
이걸 직접 차도록 하게
그렇게 할 수는 없어요
왜 그런 줄 알아요?
당신이 엿 먹인다고
생각해요
밖에 아무도 없다고
당신하고 나 둘뿐이죠
좋아요
당신하고 나 둘뿐이에요
그거 알아요?
직접 날 잡아야 될 거에요
이럴 시간이 없네
해보자구요
좋을거에요
뭘 보고 싶은지
말해 보세요
난 거짓말 하지 않았네
저 반지 보세요
결혼반지를 끼고 있잖아요
칼, 날 속였어요
날 속였어
넌 가족이 있냐고
물어봤어
그랬었지
하지만 더 이상은 아냐
네
아니, 아니에요
아무 문제 없어요
지금 밖으로 나갑니다
그거 멋졌어요
멋졌어요
호텔 종업원에게 돈 주고
걸라고 했나요?
그렇게 한 건가요?
루크서장이었어
널 데리고 나오는데
1분 주었네
루크 서장이라니
루크 서장
우...루크 서장
칼, 그거 참 공식적으로
들리는군요
전에 말했듯이 당신하고 나
둘뿐인 것 같아요
당신하고 나...
그러니 날 잡아야 돼요
프랭크, 프랭크
날 믿어야 해
이 사람들은 아주 당황했어
프랭크 그들은 화가 났어
넌 그들의 은행을 턴거야
넌 돈을 훔치고
그 나라에서 살고 있어
이렇게 될 거라고 말했잖아
하지만 다르게 끝날 수 있네
실수 하지 마라
그거 좋았어요
좋았어요, 칼
계속 그 거짓말로
밀어 붙여요
계속 밀어 붙여요
밀어 붙여서 진실처럼
만들어요
널 죽일거야
그 문으로 걸어 나가면
정말인가요?
그래
아이가 있나요? 칼
4살짜리 딸이 있네
딸한테 맹세할 수 있나요?
맹세해요?
그거 정말 멋졌어요, 칼
내가 잡았어요
괜찮아요
움직여
이봐, 공식적으로 하고 싶어요
프랭크 아백내일은 자수했어요
이해했나요?
어디로 데려가나요?
나도 가야 되요
그를 어디로 데려가나요?
나도 차에 타게 해줘요
이봐...나도 차에 태워줘요
걱정하지마라, 프랭크
미국으로 데려갈
자료가 있어
걱정하지 마
칼
착륙하면 아버지한테
전화 걸 수 있게 해준다는
약속 잊으면 안돼요
그냥 텔레비젼에 대한
얘기들을 할 거에요
칼, 봐요
루과디 공항이
바로 저기 있네요
404번 활주로
프랭크 자네 아버지는
돌아가셨네
미안하네
집에 가까이 가니
말 안할 수가 없군
그랜드센트럴역에서 기차를 타려고
하다가 계단에서 떨어지셨네
자네한테 전하고 싶지는 않았네
거짓말을 했군요, 그렇죠?
얘기할 수 있다고 했잖아요
칼, 왜 그런 소리를 한거에요
왜 그런 소리를 한거에요
얘기할 수 있다고 했잖아요
그는 떨어져서 목이 부러졌네
미안하네
정말 안됐네
난 토하고 싶어요
괜찮네
토하고 싶어요
화장실로 데려가게
젠장...
오 아빠...
자리에 앉으셔야 돼요
두번이나 말씀 드렸어요
-착륙합니다
-미안합니다
-당신들 모두...
-프랭크 이제 나오게
프랭크?
6분후에 착륙합니다
자리에 앉아주세요
프랭크 문 열어
프랭크
프랭크, 프랭크
모두다 자리에
앉아 계세요
FBI 입니다
자리에 앉아계세요
하느님 맙소사...
이름이 뭐니?
엄마는 어디 있니?
기다려
FBI다. 손 올려
칼, 제발 차에 태워 주세요
차에 태워 주세요
머리 숙이게
이 범죄의 무게를
계산해 봤을 때
당신이 저지른 무례하고
남을 현혹시키는 행동들은
미국법에 따라
당신을 미성년자로
인정해 달라는 요구를
무시할 수 밖에 없습니다
애틀란타에 있는 중범죄 교도소에서
12년형을 받을 것을 선고하고
복역기간동안 격리 시킬 것을
강력하게 권고합니다
메리 크리스마스, 프랭크
이봐, 만화책 좀 가져왔어
플래시
딸은 어때요?
이름이 뭐죠?
그레이스
나도 몰라
엄마하고 시카고에 살아
자주 보지 못했어
가방에는 뭐가 있어요?
공항으로 가는 중이었어
미네소타에 위조범이 있어
세상에...
미치게 만드는군
수표를 가지고 있나요?
그래 가져왔네
뉴욕 저축대부은행의
수표를 위조했어
언더우드에 있는
인쇄기를 사용했네
은행의 창구직원이예요
다시 말해봐
분명히 창구직원이예요, 칼
은행에서는 받을때마다
손도장을 찍어요
계속해서 찍게 되면
닳게 돼요
숫자가 언제나 망가지죠
6번 그 다음에 9번
그것들이 먼저 망가지죠
고마워
이걸 봐줬으면 좋겠네
어떻게 생각하는지
말해주게
이건 가짜군요
어떻게 그냥 보고 알지?
모서리가 이상해요
이 수표들은 손으로 잘랐어요
안 맞아요
종이가 이중으로 겹쳤어요
은행수표로는
너무 무거워요
자성잉크가 손에 묻어나요
떴어요
이건 MICR 잉크가 아니에요
초벌잉크 같아요
문구점에서 살 수 있는 것
말이에요
프랭크
FBI 금융범죄국에서
일할 생각 있나?
여기서 이미 직업을
잡았어요
우편물을 배달해요
프랭크, 우린 자네를
감옥에서 꺼낼 힘이 있네
남은 형량동안 정부를
위해서 일한다면
FBI 보호하에 보석으로
나올 수 있네
누구 보호하에?
FBI 10대 수배자
안녕하세요
전 프랭크 아백내일입니다
오늘부터 여기서
일하기로 되어 있는데요
여기로 보내세요
FBI에서 다시 조사하죠
아백내일씨가 왔습니다
다시 전화하겠네
칼
FBI에 온걸 환영한다
어디서 일할지 보여주지
칼, 얼마나 여기서
일해야 되죠?
아침 8시 15분부터
오후 5시까지
점심시간은 45분이네
아니...
제 말은 얼마나 오랫동안?
매일...
매일이네, 프랭크
보내줄 수 없네
수표 사기
-어서 와
-안녕 칼
뭐하세요?
지금은 곤란해, 프랭크
주말을 위해서
책상을 비우고 있어
내일 일하러 와도 될까요?
내일은 토요일이야
딸을 보러 시카고로
날아갈 거야
월요일에 돌아올 거네
이름이 그레이스였죠?
그게 내 계획이야
그럼 전 월요일까지
뭐하죠?
미안하네
그건 도와줄 수가 없군
실례하네
핸래티입니다
아 네. 바꿔주세요
소야부인, 안녕하세요?
BBI의 여행사 직원한테서 나온
수표가 12장 더 있습니다
검거
시카고와 샌프란시스코로 가는
아메리칸 항공 355편
지금 탑승하십시요
어떻게 한거지? 프랭크
루이지애나에서 변호사 시험을
어떻게 통과했지?
여기서 뭐하는 거예요
들어봐요
이 모든 일들에
끌어들여서 미안해요
유럽으로 가는게 나을걸
감옥에서 죽을거야
미국내에서 도망치려고 하면
아틀랜타로 돌아가서
15년을 살아야 할거야
나도 알아요
자네를 석방시키는데
4년이 걸렸네
FBI에 있는 내 상관과
미법무장관에게
네가 도망가지 않을거라고
확신시켜야 했지
왜 그랬죠?
넌 그냥 아이일뿐이야
당신 아이가 아니예요
시카고에 간다고
말했잖아요
내 딸이 이번 주말에
날 못 본대
스키타러 갔어
4살이라고 했잖아요
거짓말 했군요
내가 떠날때 4살이었어
지금은 15살이야
내 아내는 11년 전에
재혼을 했어
그레이스를 다시
매년 볼 수 있네
이해 못 하겠어요
물론 넌 할 수 있어
이제는 거짓으로 사는 걸
그만두게
오늘밤 떠나도록 해주겠네
널 막지는 않겠어
왜냐하면 월요일에
돌아올 걸 알기 때문이네
그래요?
내가 돌아올 줄
어떻게 알죠?
보라구
프랭크
아무도 쫓고 있지 않아
아메리칸 항공 131편
지금 탑승해주세요
좋아요
앨리스, 그가 전화했었나?
아뇨. 안했어요
좋은 아침입니다
이 사건을 의논하기 위해서
회의를 소집했습니다
수표 위조범이 애리조나에서
지우고 변조된 수표를
사용했습니다
이 미확인범인은
큰 놈입니다
사용한 수표의 액수가
다섯 자리를 넘어 갑니다
늦어서 죄송해요
미안합니다
래이더 요원 책상에 복원된
수표가 있습니다
가서 살펴보도록 하죠
모든 점에서 인상적이군
원래 금액은 60달러였던 것 같군
제가 봐도 될까요?
일주일전에
플래그스태프 은행에서 바꾼거네
은행에서 만육천달러를 찾았지
진짜 수표에요
그래
지워졌어
진짜가 아닌건 서명이야
완벽해요, 칼
제 말은...
이건 염산이나
표백제가 아니에요
아냐. 뭔가 새로운거지
어쩌면 매니큐어
제거제인지도 모르지
아세톤은 잉크를 지우니까...
확실하진 않네
어떻게 그렇게 했나? 프랭크
어떻게 루이지애나의 변호사 시험을
속일 수 있었나?
전 속이지 않았어요
2주일동안 공부를 해서
통과했어요
그거 사실인가?
정말이야?
이 자식 우편함에서
수표를 훔쳤어요
지워 버리고
자기 이름을 넣었어요
그 지역 출신이라는거야?
저라면 은행에
먼저 전화를 걸어서
잔고를 확인하겠어요
찾을 돈이 충분히 있는지
확인하겠지
바로 그거예요
칼. 이 자식은
아주 똑똑한 것 같아요
이제 우리가 해야 할 일은
그를 잡는거군요
아침에 바로 시작하세
그 지역의 명단을 뽑아봐
애리조나, 캘리포니아...
프랭크 아백내일 주니어는 26년 동안
결혼 생활을 했습니다
세명의 아들과 중서부지방에서
조용히 살고 있습니다
1974년에 감옥에서
풀려난 이래로
세계에서 가장 뛰어난 수표 위조범들을
FBI가 잡는데 도움을 주었고
은행 사기와 위조에 관한
세계 제일의 권위자 중 하나입니다
프랭크는 또한 은행과
포춘지 500대 기업에서
매일 사용하는 안전 수표들을
많이 디자인했습니다
그 대가로 이 회사들은
프랭크 아백내일 주니어에게
일년에 수백만 달러를
지불합니다
프랭크와 칼은 아직까지
친한 친구로 지냅니다
The End
네오디엔지 자막팀
http://neodng.com